<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>mjladd</title>
 <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.mjladd.com"/>
 <updated>2013-05-29T19:30:49-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.mjladd.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Michael Ladd</name>
   <email>mjladd@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Pushing Forward</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2013/04/06/pushing-forward"/>
   <updated>2013-04-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2013/04/06/pushing-forward</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking alot about operations lately, how to move forward and how to keep people intersted in the work that they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of concepts that makes me really respect how esty performs is their focus. They seems to have a great ability to focus on a core set of software and development processes and not be distracted by every new option that comes along. There is a constant stream of new software, ideas, new libraries, etc &amp;#8230; that offers a better, simpler, shinier way to do something. I am impressed by the discipline of Etsy to remain true to what they feel is the right way to operate while still being undeniably successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it is the process of debt and support that keeps my options limited (in a good way). Every new thing must be maintained, monitoring and upgraded. This quickly stretches out the ability of a team to keep up on necessary security and configuration issues. I think every new thing must be defensible in its addition and all the better when it can be offered with the retirement of something old.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Progress</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2013/03/09/progress"/>
   <updated>2013-03-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2013/03/09/progress</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two months down in 2013 and I like to check in with year goals and progress. The primary priorities this year are coding and math. I&amp;#8217;ve pushed aside reading aside from lunch hours and have done almost nothing with music. Spare time is so minimal now, I have to make the most with what little there is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of day, after dinner, cleanup, a bit of time with the little one, I have maybe an hour to work. I&amp;#8217;ve been spending most of this time working on code. I have completed codecademy work in both ruby and python. I think I&amp;#8217;m to the point where I need to stop doing little excercises and start working on something real in order to learn anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Math progress is much slower. Everytime I dig in I find myself going backwards and finding more and more of what I have forgotten. I&amp;#8217;m looking to find the most practical and useful applications, but many of the tutorials use primary concepts that I&amp;#8217;ve long forgotten. I still get the panic when looking at a page of symbols that I have no framework for. So I continue to go backwards and do more exercises to try and remember so much forgotten work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy with the focus and discipline. Priorities are much clearer now and answering the question of what next is simple. Although progress is slow, persistence is all I have now. Marking off each day of the chain by doing &amp;#8216;something&amp;#8217; and having the confidence that this is all building into something I can only start to envision.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Revenge: Bury Your Enemies</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2013/01/14/revenge"/>
   <updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2013/01/14/revenge</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m about 99% positive that most of the progress I&amp;#8217;ve made in my life is due to my teachers. Not the good ones (there were a few, but not enough), but the bad ones. The awful, lazy teachers who did nothing but make me want to have the revenge of living well. I can think of two math instructors I had who worked hard and tried to communicate, and I did great in those classes .. but the rest mostly walked through the same lesson plans they used for decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why am I studying math at home while my wife and newborn sleep? Because I had teachers who cared so little for instruction and doing anything beyond going through the motions that they left me with almost no interest and a lot of fear of my own ignorance. Revenge for me was failing math in high school, but getting a minor in applied physics. That minor was hard won, and I had some really lousy teachers in college as well, but I had enough anger to get me through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the teachers were bad, but not bad enough to kill my interest, or maybe they just made me mad enough to keep going. Even as I kid I knew what they were doing was wrong and they were cheating their students. I think alot about where I came from and how much work it took to get out. I&amp;#8217;m not very smart, but I have enough anger to make me work hard, and that seems to be what was needed to progress, move forward and escape. I&amp;#8217;m not successful, but I&amp;#8217;m further along they I should be. I gave up a lot of sleep to end up with a decent job and I have great parents who supported me. But I don&amp;#8217;t think anything motivated me more than frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way there was a lot of &amp;#8221;I&amp;#8217;ll show you&amp;#8221;, but that&amp;#8217;s tempered now. I did do it and now I have to take advantage of what I have. I can look back and let myself off the hook .. but just a little. Just enough to appreciate what I have, but not to get slow and lazy. I feel lucky, but it&amp;#8217;s been an earned luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to read this McNally &lt;a href='http://southeastreview.org/onlineissue1/mcnally.php'&gt;writeup&lt;/a&gt; on a regular basis. T.C. Boyle says it best, &amp;#8220;Bury your enemies, and bury &amp;#8216;em deep&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Year: 2013</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2013/01/05/new-year"/>
   <updated>2013-01-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2013/01/05/new-year</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2012 was a pretty hard year to catorize and looking back at music/book purchases it seems to be one of continuously paring down the unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that last 5-6 years I&amp;#8217;ve been working to puchase less to make sure that I actually read and listen to what I own. There are the occasionnal trigger purchases, but many fewer than before. I am trying to pare down, reduce and throw away that which is unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The house took a great deal of work for the summer. I spent a lot of time busting out concreate and fixing the lawn. The drought took out a lot of my work, but I&amp;#8217;m pretty happy with the results. This year will be more of that work with a back porch that needs to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did manage to work on an EP of music that I hadn&amp;#8217;t planned on. I had gone a solid year with dismissing everything that I wrote. I was happy to put in the time and get a bit of music down before life got busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The little one was the focus for the last part of the year. It&amp;#8217;s been great, hard, challenging and rewarding. Jen is the real champion and I&amp;#8217;m just the side-kick for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m planning for 2013 to be a year of less consumption and more production. I have a todo list focusing on new work, reducing the useless and moving everything forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best Music 2012&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vijay Iyer Trio - Accelerando&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Matt Halmovitz &amp;amp; Christopher O&amp;#8217;Riley - Shuffle.Play.Listen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Jason Isbell and The 400 Unit - Live From Alabama&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Godspeed You! Black Emperor - Allelujah! Don&amp;#8217;t Bend! Ascend!&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Flying Lotus - Until the Quiet Comes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Donald Fagen - Sunken Condos&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dan Deacon - America&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Christian Scott - Christian aTunde Adjuah&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Baroness - Yellow &amp;amp; Green&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Bad Plus - Made Possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best Reading 2012&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skippy Dies - Paul Murray&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Pale King - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Suttree - Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Art of Fielding - Chad Harbach&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Infinite Jest - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Telegraph Avenue - Michael Chabon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2012</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/12/18/reading"/>
   <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/12/18/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary: This was the year of David Foster Wallace. I tried to read/listen/absorb everything I could find on his work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2012&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous delivery and DevOps A Quickstart Guide - Paul Swartout&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;DevOps for Developers - Michael Hüttermann&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Blood Meridian, or the Evening Redness in the West- Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Both Flesh and Not: Essays - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Listen to This - Alex Ross&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;So Good They Can&amp;#8217;t Ignore You: Why Skills Trump Passion in the Quest for Work You Love - Cal Newport&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Victory Lab: The Secret Science of Winning Campaigns - Issenberg, Sasha&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Telegraph Avenue - Chabon, Michael&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Future Perfect: The Case for Progress in a Networked Age - Johnson, Steven&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Leaving the Atocha Station - Ben Lerner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fooling Houdini: Magicians, Mentalists, Math Geeks, and the Hidden Powers of the Mind - Alex Stone&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Understanding David Foster Wallace - Marshall Boswell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Consider David Foster Wallace: Critical Essays - David Hering&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Every Love Story is a Ghost Story: A Life of David Foster Wallace - D.T. Max&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Elegant Complexity - Greg Carlisle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Infinite Jest - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;David Foster Wallace&amp;#8217;s Infinite Jest - Stephen J. Burn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Some Remarks: Essays and Other Writing - Neal Stephenson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Book of Drugs: A Memoir - Mike Doughty&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Team Geek: A Software Developer&amp;#8217;s Guide to Working Well with Others - Brian W. Fitzpatrick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ship It!: A Practical Guide to Successful Software Projects - Jared Richardson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Developer&amp;#8217;s Code: What Real Programmers Do - Ka Wai Cheung&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Finding Ultra: Rejecting Middle Age, Becoming One of the World&amp;#8217;s Fittest Men, and Discovering Myself - Rich Roll&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No Country for Old Men - Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Road - Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Girl With Curious Hair - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Musimathics: The Mathematical Foundations of Music, Volume 1 - Gareth Loy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Legacy of David Foster Wallace - Samuel Cohen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Code Simplicity: The Science of Software Development - Max Kanat-Alexander&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fitness for Geeks: Real Science, Great Nutrition, and Good Health - Bruce W. Perry&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Art of Fielding - Chad Harbach&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Oblivion: Stories - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Broom of the System - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Suttree - Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Conversations with David Foster Wallace - Stephen J. Burn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Sugar Frosted Nutsack - Mark Leyner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Wrecking Crew: The Inside Story of Rock and Roll&amp;#8217;s Best-Kept Secret - Kent Hartman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;My Cousin, My Gastroenterologist - Mark Leyner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Tetherballs of Bougainville - Mark Leyner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Managing Infrastructure with Puppet - James Loppe&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Pragmatic Version Control Using Git - Travis Swicegood&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Apprenticeship Patterns: Guidance for the Aspiring Software Craftsman - Dave Hoover&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Et Tu, Babe - Mark Leyner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tooth Imprints on a Corn Dog - Mark Leyner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Brief Interviews with Hideous Men - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Motti - Asaf Schurr&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Marriage Plot - Jeffrey Eugenides&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Pale King - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Supposedly Fun Thing I&amp;#8217;ll Never Do Again - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;On Writing - Stephen King&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Spiderland - Scott Tennent&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Consider the Lobster and Other Essays - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Achieving Business Value from Technology: A Practical Guide for Today&amp;#8217;s Executive - Tony Murphy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Although Of Course You End Up Becoming Yourself: A Road Trip with David Foster Wallace - David Lipsky&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Elements of Style - William Strunk&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Skippy Dies - Paul Murray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>dfw 2012 project</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/12/17/dfw2012"/>
   <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/12/17/dfw2012</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My big reading project for this year was to read everything written by and about David Foster Wallace. Here are the final stats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;300+ journal articles (interviews, criticism, etc)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;a few hundred hours of audiobooks, tributes and interviews&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;17 books (~5874 pages .. with Infinite Jest as 20% of the total effort)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a good project, a lot of fun and a bit of a challenge to be in that mindset for nearly nine months of reading. It wasn&amp;#8217;t exclusive, I also made it through 25-30 other books so far this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s hard to put into words how DFW&amp;#8217;s writing makes me think and feel, to me he&amp;#8217;s a goddamned magician.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I read &amp;#8216;Good Old Neon&amp;#8217; from Oblivion, I wait for the moment. It&amp;#8217;s never as good as it was the first time, because it&amp;#8217;s not the surprise that it once was. I remember the feeling, in the second floor of the Skokie Public Library, reading bits of &amp;#8216;Oblivion&amp;#8217; when I should have been studying for my MCSE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s on page 180, about halfway through. The narrator is gone (literally) and perspective has shifted and I remember feeling as if I was floating, as if I was inside the story as a observer, just as the narrator changed to the omniscient view and I saw myself as the character David Wallace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a goddamned magic trick and I look each time for the misdirection, but never catch it. Now it&amp;#8217;s just anticipation and a humming inside my brain that I get when bearing witness to something truly good. It&amp;#8217;s art that connects and it feels like an amplifier on my own thoughts. It&amp;#8217;s the buzz I get from reading something good and worked over with and eye towards craftsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get something similar from &amp;#8220;Everything is Green&amp;#8221;, but it&amp;#8217;s different. While &amp;#8216;GON&amp;#8217; is showy, its showy in a way that feels like a singular work, no one else could have written it and it&amp;#8217;s voice is individual. &amp;#8216;EIG&amp;#8217; hits me like the work of someone way too clever and is showing off how they can fill a story in so short of a space that still provides the reader with everything they need to know about the characters in three short pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all of his work has this magical moment, but I enjoy it when I catch it. It&amp;#8217;s what makes the effort worthwhile. The digging a little deeper below the surface to find the real art.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>dt9</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/10/11/dt9"/>
   <updated>2012-10-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/10/11/dt9</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With life about to get a lot busier, I wanted to finish a bit of &lt;a href='http://mjladd.com/music.html'&gt;music&lt;/a&gt;. For the last year, every piece of music I wrote I hated immediately afterwards. I threw out a half-dozen tracks and started over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of this was done very quickly, often recording single takes and cleaning up afterwards. The production is a little sloppy at times, but I focused mostly on the song itself, ensuring the form of the tune was tight and the melodies memorable (which is a change from my usual focus on texture).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Logstash init script</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/08/31/logstash-init"/>
   <updated>2012-08-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/08/31/logstash-init</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Getting init to play nice with running a java jar file as a service was a bit of a hassle. The built-in daemonize function wasn&amp;#8217;t able to correctly create a .pid file so here&amp;#8217;s something that finally worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class='bash'&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/sh
#
# chkconfig: 2345 70 40
# description: logstash startup script
#
LOGSTASH=/opt/logstash/logstash-1.1.1-monolithic.jar
CONF=/opt/logstash/logstash.conf
TMPDIR=/dev/shm
export TMPDIR

. /etc/rc.d/init.d/functions

RETVAL=0

case &amp;quot;$1&amp;quot; in
   start)
      echo -n &amp;quot;Starting logstash: &amp;quot;
      [ -f $LOGSTASH ] || exit 1
      daemon &amp;quot;java -jar $LOGSTASH agent -f $CONF &amp;amp;&amp;quot; 2&amp;gt;&amp;gt; /var/log/messages
      pgrep -f /opt/logstash/logstash-*-monolithic.jar &amp;gt; /var/run/logstash.pid
      RETVAL=$?
      echo
      [ $RETVAL -eq 0 ] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; touch /var/lock/subsys/logstash
      ;;

  stop)
      echo -n &amp;quot;Shutting down logstash: &amp;quot;
      killproc  logstash 
      RETVAL=$?
      echo
      [ $RETVAL -eq 0 ] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; rm -f /var/lock/subsys/logstash
      ;;

  restart|reload)
    $0 stop
    $0 start
    RETVAL=$?
    ;;
  status)
    status logstash 
    RETVAL=$?
    ;;
  *)
    echo &amp;quot;Usage: $0 {start|stop|restart|status}&amp;quot;
    exit 1
esac

exit $RETVAL&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Good start to the day</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/06/04/am-start"/>
   <updated>2012-06-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/06/04/am-start</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fine way to begin the week, all mornings should start this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4:30 am - up -&amp;gt; check email/sites/iced tea/plan workout&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;5:00 am - stretching/workout&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;6:00 am - water plants/lawn (grass is sprouting and garden is showing some promise)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;6:30 am - breakfast (sausage/bagel/hashbrowns/eggs/coffee/smoothie)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;7:00 am - piano practice&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;7:30 am - prep for work (shower/pack/plan)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;8:15 am - out the door&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: new headphones at work w/ some degree of noise isolation may help save my sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Yardwork</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/05/29/on-yardwork"/>
   <updated>2012-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/05/29/on-yardwork</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spent the holiday weekend working on the yard. We tried to find landscape service, but they were all either too busy to return calls or continually canecelled meetings. Hence, DIY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last two months, I raced home from work to shovel down a quick dinner and get outside and work until it turned dark. Everything from breaking up90 square feet of concrete to pulling out and endless number of daylillies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a half-day and an extra day off of work, I was able to knock out the last chunk of work. According to the fitbit, I put 26+ miles of walking w/out even leaving my yard. I put down around 9 cubic meters of soil and spread 22 cubic feet of mulch. I also built two raised garden beds and filled them with a mix of vegetables and flowes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I get to wait out the grass seed and water and hope that I&amp;#8217;m not filling in my large dirt hole with sod in another month or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='yardwork 2012' height='287' src='/images/backyard_2012_rev01.jpg' title='Yardwork 2012' width='512' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Art of Fielding</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/05/09/the-art-of-fielding"/>
   <updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/05/09/the-art-of-fielding</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This passage from &amp;#8216;The Art of Fielding&amp;#8217; really rang true for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schwartz cherished these private, diligent hours. All day long, no matter how hard he worked, no matter what he accomplished, a voice in his head berated him for his laziness, his sloth, his inability to concentrate. His concerns were trivial. His knowledge of history was shallow. His Latin sucked, and his Greek was worse. How did he expect to grasp Aurelius and Epictetus, inquired the voice, when he could barely string to Latin words together? Only here, long after midnight, when everyone else was sleeping, when nothing was expected of him, could Schwartz convince himself that he was working hard enough. These hours felt stolen, added to his life. The voice fell quiet. Even the pain in his knees subsided. p. 102&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On the Temperature of Water</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/04/03/on-the-temperature-of-water"/>
   <updated>2012-04-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/04/03/on-the-temperature-of-water</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading Grant Achatz&amp;#8217;s book on Alinea is a pretty fair exercise in self-aggrandization, but there was a nice moment I pulled out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a discussion about not wanting table linens and the of water glasses damaging table surfaces. They worked to find the correct water temperature that would not cause condensation, while also being appropriatly cool. They were able to retain the aesthetics of a clean looking table design w/out compromising on the customer&amp;#8217;s need for a refreshing drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love reading about obsessive little details and how much people care to stay true to their vision. Anyone who has a concept and stays true to them while still serving the needs of their customers is the magic venn diagram of success.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Academics</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/04/02/on-academics"/>
   <updated>2012-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/04/02/on-academics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having spent far too much time dealing w/ academics, I&amp;#8217;ve had the time to gain a few opinins via both good and awful experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='the_bad_stuff'&gt;The Bad Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id='bad_teachers'&gt;bad teachers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad teachers can kill your will to learn. There were plenty of classes where I realized how little work was needed and I was able to make better use of my time by hitting the library or preparing for other classes. Classes that expect little from their students will get that back in return. You learn to see who is actually burning calories trying to communicate and who is filling in the hours, or even worse doing damage to your will to learn. There&amp;#8217;s a trait you can see for those who have the gift of appearing knowledgeable but there&amp;#8217;s a pretty shallow pond to that knowledge and you realize that they know more about how to keep their job than how to teach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='bike_shedding'&gt;bike shedding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Way too much focus on academic wanking and arguemnts about nonsense. They can be fun, but looking back they were mostly empty calories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='the_good_stuff'&gt;The Good Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id='access_to_time'&gt;access to time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never had a much time as I did as a student. Even when taking 18 hours of classes and working 2-3 jobs there was always extra time comparing to working 40+ hours in a straight job, maintaining a relationship and taking care of a home. This was a greatest time to look into every interest I had and dive into whatever I wanted at the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='access_to_materials'&gt;access to materials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not as relevant now, having access to a well stocked studio for 80 hours or so a week was fantastic for me. I spent more time at the studio then I did my own home and was really the only time I felt that I learned anything applicable about music. During my senior year while still balancing a job and prepping for a senior composition recital I spent as much time as possible in the studio, trying every plugin, microphone, instrument possible to learn what will work. The great side affect was in these early days of digital recording gave me plenty of time to learn how to troubleshoot. I learned how to break problems down into the smallest components and think logically through the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='good_teachers'&gt;good teachers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a few, not enough. The good ones changed the way I thought and the bad ones taught me how to sniff out BS. You learn to see who is actually burning calories tring to communicate and who is filling in the hours, or even worse doing damage to your will to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='ass_kicking'&gt;ass kicking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;College was a pretty normal distribution in terms of ass kicking. The first couple of years were tough. Having never really gotten out of a small town, it was a bit overwhealming. Once I came to grips with the environment I buried myself in work, pushing myself as far as possible in terms of missing sleep by never workouts. I was able to reign it in after awhile and managed to focus more on what truly needed to get done. Through my senior year of college and the year-and-a-half of grad school I felt that I really made progress and pushed myself as far as possible. This was the feeling I was looking for when I went back to school for a PhD (enormous bust) and even a second masters (very expensive bust).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s good to remember that these waves come and go and do the same in any work environment. After a couple of years of crappy jobs I think I&amp;#8217;m at a place where I can kick ass again for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Review of 2011</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/03/16/Review-of-2011"/>
   <updated>2012-03-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/03/16/Review-of-2011</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Way late on this, but this draft has been sitting around for awhle. It was a pretty awful year for films, w/ Moneyball being the only film that sticks out in my memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music (no particular order):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bill Frisell - All we are Saying&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bon Iver - s/t&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Elbow - Build a Rocket Boys&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fitz and the tandrums - Pickin&amp;#8217; up the Pieces&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Goddamn electric bill - Jazz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The great book of john - s/t&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Jason isbell and the 400 unit - Here we Rest&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;My Morning Jacket - Circuital&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Russian Circles -Empros&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tom Waits - Bad as Me&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;TV on the Radio - Nine Types of Light&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The War on Drugs - Slave Ambient&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books (no particular order):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Creative Habit - Twyla Tharp&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;God is Dead - Ron Currie Jr.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The F-ing Epic Twitter Quest of @MayorEmanuel - Dan Sinker&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Slaughterhouse Five - Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Recording the Beatles - Kevin Ryan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Here There and Everywhere - Geoff Emerick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The War of Art (re-read) - Steven Pressfield&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Confederacy of Dunces (re-read) - John Kennedy Toole&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Whole New Mind - Daniel Pink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last.fm = 445 different artists in the last 12 months. The idea of statically listening to the same music over and over until I die sound miserable. It&amp;#8217;s like reading the same ten books over-and-over and just letting a part of my brain shrivel away. There&amp;#8217;s too much good stuff out there to ignore. I need to keep my mind open and my preconceived notions buried away. I&amp;#8217;m glad that I use something like last.fm to remind myself to keep looking and keep searching for new music.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Changing Puppet Config Paths Under Passenger</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/03/13/Changing-Puppet-Paths"/>
   <updated>2012-03-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/03/13/Changing-Puppet-Paths</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Making some progress in getting our puppet manifests under a capistrano script. Everything has been under version control for awhile, but it&amp;#8217;s been my plan to get a proper deployment configuration set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I could get capistrano set up, I needed to make sure that puppet was running out of a new path, since cap is going to be removing and recreating symlinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir /etc/puppet/current&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;code&gt;mv /etc/puppet/* /etc/puppet/current&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/etc/puppet/puppet.conf&lt;br /&gt; &lt;code&gt;[main]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;code&gt;    tagmap = /etc/puppet/current/tagmail.conf&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;code&gt;[master]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;code&gt;    modulepath = /etc/puppet/current/modules&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The missing piece was remembering that we run the puppetmaster out of passenger and passenger was not finding the path changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding the following to:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/puppet/rack/puppetmaster/config.ru&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;code&gt;ARGV &amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;quot;--confdir=/etc/puppet/current&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A restart of httpd and all was well. The puppetmaster was running out of the new configuration path. The next step is to deploy the configuration via capistrano.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Blog</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2012/03/12/new-blog"/>
   <updated>2012-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2012/03/12/new-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spent too much time moving this over from wordpress to jekyll, but I did take the time to pull together a bunch of old entries from other blogs. It was a trip to go back and read through stuff well over ten years old and then promptly dump most of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a half-dozen wanna-be articles ready to be written, now that I&amp;#8217;m done poking around the config side I need to sit down and do the hard part of actually writing.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2011</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2011-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2011&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Calculus Diaries - Jennifer Ouellette&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1958: The Year That Changed Everything - Fred Kaplan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Microsound - Curtis Roads&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Game of Thrones - George R.R. Martin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Scorecasting - Tobias Moskowitz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Switch - Chip Heath&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ignore Everybody - Hugh MacLeod&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The War of Art - Steven Pressfield&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;10 Minute Toughness - Jason Selk&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Checklist Manifesto - Atul Gawande&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Creative Habit - Twyla Tharp&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Evil Plans - Hugh MacLeod&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Programming Amazon EC2 - Jurg van Vilet&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Talent Code - Daniel Coyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Emotional Intellegence 2.0 - Travis Bradberry&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Confederacy of Dunces - John Kenndey Toole&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Whole New Mind - Daniel Pink&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bird by Bird - Anne Lamott&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;God is Dead - Ron Currie Jr.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Practicing: A Musician&amp;#8217;s Return to Music - Glen Kurtz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Coltrane: The Story of a Sound - Ben Ratliff&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Chasin&amp;#8217; the Trane - J.C. Thomas&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The House that Trane Built - Ashley Kahn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ascenion: John Coltane and his Quest - Eric Nisenson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;John Coltrane - Bill Cole&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Love Supreme: The Story of John Coltrane&amp;#8217;s Signature Album - Ashley Kahn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;John Coltrane: His Life and Music - Lewis Porter&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Talent is Overrated - Geoff Colvin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nudge - Richard Thaler&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mockingjay - Suzanne Collins&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Web Operations - John Allspaw&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Kingdom on the Waves - M.T. Anderson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Night Gardener - George Pelecanos&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Discover Your Inner Economist - Tyler Cowen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Being Geek - Michael Lopp&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Mathematician&amp;#8217;s Lament - Paul Lockhart&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Anything You Want - Derek Sivers&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cat&amp;#8217;s Cradle - Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Light House: A Trifle - William Monahan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Biopunk - Marcus Wohlsen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Little Brother - Cory Doctorow&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater - Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Magician King - Lev Grossman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ready Player One - Ernest Cline&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Vision Quest - Terry Davis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Fucking Epic Twitter Quest of @MayorEmanuel - Dan Sinker&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Zombie Spaceship Wasteland - Patton Oswalt&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Slaughterhouse-Five - Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reamde - Neal Stephenson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Context - Cory Doctorow&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Medium Raw - Anthony Bourdain&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Blood, Bones and Butter - Gabrielle Hamilton&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Life on the Line - Grant Achatz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Recording the Beatles - Kevin Ryan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Steve Jobs - Walter Isaacson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Pragmatic Thinking and Learning - Andy Hunt&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Here, There and Everywhere - Geoff Emerick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Nerdist Way - Chris Hardwick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All You Need is Ears - George Martin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;slideology - Nancy Duarte&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Power Ballads - Wil Boast&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Pulphead - John Jeremiah Sullivan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Vist from the Goon Squad - Jennifer Egan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Art of Unix Programming - Eric S. Raymond&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Everyday Scripting with Ruby - Brian Marick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Meet the New Boss(es)</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/09/04/meet-the-new-boss%28es%29"/>
   <updated>2011-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/09/04/meet-the-new-boss(es)</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the last five years I&amp;#8217;ve been pretty serious about weightlifting. Aside from a month off following surgery I never went a week without a minimum of three-days of weight-training and often went 4-5 days a week (which a short period of doing two-a-days when Jen was out of town).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting older has made recovery times slower and a couple of injuries are forcing me to slow down. I&amp;#8217;m committed to taking time off now that will allow me to return to heavier lifting in about a year. My goal is to continue lifting until at least 45 yrs old. I&amp;#8217;ve hit most of my lifting goals with the exception of a 500 lb deadlift (I was at least two years away from that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I&amp;#8217;m going to focus on recovery and conditioning with two of my new best friends; the kettlebell and interval timer. Rather than pulling 400 lbs off the floor, I&amp;#8217;m struggling to perform a 45 lb turkish get up and doing timed kettlebell swings. It really is an ego check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months, I&amp;#8217;ve dropped 28 lbs and I&amp;#8217;ll likely have to shop for new clothes since I&amp;#8217;m starting to swim in my own shirts. It sucks, but I&amp;#8217;m making the best of it. It&amp;#8217;s a minor bump and will soon fade.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On code..</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/08/07/on-code"/>
   <updated>2011-08-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/08/07/on-code</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thinking back on taking programming programming classes in school, java and c++, I couldn&amp;#8217;t have been more bored. I had no reason to care about flipping the order of characters or determining how long a string was. It all meant nothing to me. The tiny little details that at the end of a semester added up to .. nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I found myself working with linux and learning about bash, and now .. I can actually do something with code. I can write cronjobs that execute when I need them to, I can write scripts that execute when the server starts up. I can ensure that services are running .. I could do real work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have appreciation for the people who enjoy the tiny details, but I could never stay interested enough to stay around to the point where I could do anything of personal value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last couple of years I&amp;#8217;ve been able to work with puppet and that&amp;#8217;s been just great. With code, I can set up servers exactly how they need to be and if someone mucks around with them, the servers bounce back to their original settings. This is the kind of coding I enjoy, I can see results immediately and more importantly, I can see value immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am trying to go back and re-learn some things about code that I&amp;#8217;ve long forgotten and have never used, but it&amp;#8217;s work, and it&amp;#8217;s not fulfilling work. It&amp;#8217;s digging out parts of my brain that I&amp;#8217;ve never used, it must be the former catholic part of me that thinks suffering is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reboot</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/07/30/reboot"/>
   <updated>2011-07-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/07/30/reboot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the home purchase and wedding planning going on, there&amp;#8217;s been little time left for anything else. I&amp;#8217;ve been doing my best to keep up with my reading projects and making sure I hit the gym 3x a week, but anything else has pretty much been ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As things have settled down and with the year half-over, it&amp;#8217;s time to reboot and replan. I have a hard time feeling like I&amp;#8217;m making any progress without some structure. So this week has been spent with pile of books, a yellow legal pad and things.app. I have a pretty good idea of how the rest of the year should work out in terms of goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also happy to get a big project started at work, something I&amp;#8217;ve been working towards for the past few years. This will be a good opportunity to show off my ideas and prove that they work.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My Aircraft</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/03/06/my-aircraft"/>
   <updated>2011-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/03/06/my-aircraft</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just finished rereading &amp;#8220;The Checklist Manifesto&amp;#8221; which seems to have become one of my &amp;#8220;give it the once-over every year&amp;#8221; books. The last section is an overview of the US Airways Flight 1549 which landed in the Hudson River. The phrase &amp;#8220;my aircraft&amp;#8221; really hit me in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When things went south and Captain Sullenberger realized that both engines had lost power he look over the flight from the co-pilot Jeffrey Skiles. The book details several of the reasons why he took over (for example, the amount of flight time with that particular aircraft) but reading that single phrase encapsulates an enormous amount of discipline and ownership. The ability for someone to rely on their training without panic and to take on responsibility in the moment is tremendously impressive to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work in a pretty low-discipline field, (TMTOWTDI being one of the more well-known responses to fixing issues or getting things done) but the idea of rigor and discipline for problem solving always interests me. I envy the focus and need to concentrate on narrowing down issues to their core and finding universal ways to communicate about the problem along with determining a solution.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>George Winston live and sleep inducing</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/02/21/George-Winston-sleep-inducing"/>
   <updated>2011-02-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/02/21/George-Winston-sleep-inducing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about a few more concerts that I did the sound for. George Winston may have been the most uncomfortable performance that I ever personally witnessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winston plays sleepy/new-agey piano music that I can tolerate for maybe 2-3 tunes, but after that it just makes me tired. I was responsible for setting up microphones and running sound reinforcement for the show. I met briefly with his manager prior to the performance to ensure that things were set to his specifications. I&amp;#8217;ll never forget the look in his face when he assured me that, &amp;#8220;George will play an encore.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winston played for somewhere between 70 and 90 minutes, it all ran together. The audience was in for maybe the first third of the show, but then from my vantage point, I could see people shifting in their seats, looking around and yawning. When he finished the last tune, there was a collective leap to their feet as the audience started streaming for the doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 10 seconds after finishing the last tune, George ran back out to the stage with a guitar to play an encore of slack-key hawaiian-influenced music. It was so uncomfortable to watch him starting to play while people were actively leaving. About 60 seconds into the tune, the exit doors were covered by ushers who where trying to get people to return back to their seats. Not exactly leaving the audience wanting for more.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Result of Quality</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/02/06/result-of-quality"/>
   <updated>2011-02-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/02/06/result-of-quality</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been on a big David Simon kick since I&amp;#8217;ve been re-watching &amp;#8216;The Wire&amp;#8217; with Jen. Although it took me a few episodes to dig in when I watched it the first time, I (like many folks) became enamored without the show. Critical acclaim naming the best TV Series ever is not to be dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The side affect of &amp;#8220;The Wire&amp;#8221; (for myself) is being unable to watch any other cop-related programming without a fair amount of teeth gritting at the low quality writing and ridiculous plot lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon&amp;#8217;s show &amp;#8220;Generation Kill&amp;#8221; had the same effect on me when attempting to watch &amp;#8220;The Green Zone&amp;#8221;. Generation Kill showed a view of the Iraq War from an embedded journalist and how misconstrued so many of the efforts were. The voices of the soldiers felt real and true. Hearing lines like &amp;#8220;Get your game face on&amp;#8221; from Matt Damon in &amp;#8220;The Green Zone&amp;#8221; just made me wince. I made it about 30 minutes before giving up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a technical nerd standpoint, I love the way that Simon (or rather the directors he chooses) uses sound and visuals. Music is very rarely used unless it comes from a real source; a car radio, or music appropriate for the environment. GZ (like many hollywood films) uses silly, obvious music to tell you exactly how you should feel, &amp;#8220;this is tension, this is drama&amp;#8221; rather than letting the actors tell the story. GZ also uses the nausea inducing shaky-cam which makes me physically bothered (I shouldn&amp;#8217;t be surprised, the director, Paul Greengrass made the unwatchable Bourne films) . David Simon uses the camera to highlight the content and not obscure it. With few exceptions, Simon focuses on story above all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of quality is showing how far the bar can be raising by demonstrating the results of a valiant effort and commitment to telling a story in the truest way possible. &amp;#8220;The Green Zone&amp;#8221; was a hackneyed story with mediocre performances.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lyle Lovett vs Dwight Yoakam</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/02/06/Lyle-Lovett-vs-Dwight-Yoakam"/>
   <updated>2011-02-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/02/06/Lyle-Lovett-vs-Dwight-Yoakam</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent the summer of 1999 working sound for the Interlochen Center for the arts. It was a great opportunity to see how professional artists tour. I was amazed by how quick a touring staff is able to set up and tear down within a day. Two of the artist that made the most impression (for very different reasons) were Lyle Lovett and Dwight Yoakam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been a fan of Mr. Lovett for a number of years. His album &amp;#8220;Joshua Judges Ruth&amp;#8221; is still one of my favorites. Tremendous song writing and an amazing group of musicians. This staff and group were exactly what I expected, totally professional and ready to go. They set up full lights, sound and instruments like navy seals. When the show was ready, Lyle stepped off the bus, hot lady on his arm, both dressed like they were going to an opera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show was great and tear down was exactly like the setup. Everyone knew what they were going and it felt almost effortless. The staff and musicians were cool and confident and worked well together. The experience with Mr. Yoakam was the complete opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Dwight&amp;#8217;s stage was set, they began the sound check. Apparently they had just released a new project, but no one could remember the the single. They had to scrape up a copy of the CD to play over the PA in order to relearn the tune. The poor front-of-house tech had to play the track at least a dozen times in order for the band to memorize the chord changes. Mr. Yoakam had the safety of a teleprompter for the lyrics, but even he was struggling with the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show that night went equally as bad. There was nearly constant feedback from the monitors, and I&amp;#8217;m positive that was the last night the monitor guy was employed by the Yoakum organization. The band was adequate and Dwight was a decent showman, but there was nothing professional about it. The musicians were agitated and the roadies looked beat up and worn down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot that summer about how I want to work. I want to have the experience and confidence that I know my job and will execute as expected, even when things don&amp;#8217;t go as expected.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Milton Babbitt  5/10/16 - 1/29/11</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/29/Milton-Babbitt"/>
   <updated>2011-01-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/29/Milton-Babbitt</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just read about Milton Babbitt passing away. When I was in school, Babbitt was often brought up as an quintessential 20th Century composer. While much of his music didn&amp;#8217;t appeal to me, his idea and concepts of music have stuck in my craw. He may be best know for a well-referenced essay, &amp;#8221;&lt;a href='http://www.palestrant.com/babbitt.html'&gt;Who Cares If You Listen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, his thoughts on how series music need not appeal to the general public didn&amp;#8217;t seem to register with many composer that I met in school. They were often embittered at how little acclaim they received for their efforts and were unyielding in their need for approval while rarely giving the audience worthy material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very fond of the idea of smaller, concentrated groups performing whatever arts they enjoyed to those who also enjoyed it. This allows those who wish such activities to continue to do so without cluttering or reducing their work for easier consumption. The great thing about any art is how the finest ideas eventually leak through and those willing to listen/absorb or consume, will discover them on their own time. But&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Admittedly, if this music is not supported, the whistling repertory of the man in the street will be little affected, the concert-going activity of the conspicuous consumer of musical culture will be little disturbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But music will cease to evolve, and, in that important sense, will cease to live.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M. Babbitt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Thinking about Sonny</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/22/thinking-about-Sonny"/>
   <updated>2011-01-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/22/thinking-about-Sonny</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was a music student, I read biographies of pretty much any musician I could grab from the library: John Coltrane, Miles Davis, Pablo Casals, etc. The story of Sonny Rollins and The Bridge is one of the few that has stuck with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1959, Sonny Rollins took a break from music. Although he was one of the finest sax players at the time, he felt pressure from other musicians such as John Coltrane (who emerged from working with Thelonius Monk and a second stint with Miles Davis a reinvented musician) and Ornette Colman who were changing jazz in significant ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For three years, Sonny Rollins walked to the Williamsburg Bridge to practice. He was living in a small apartment with neighbors surrounding him so he took to the bridge to rehearse. The traffic noise forced him to develop his breathing strength to be heard and he spent hours there, occasionally working with Jackie McLean. He emerged with a new command of his instrument and formed a new quartet that recorded &amp;#8216;The Bridge&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing I miss about being a grad student, was having the time (and not being able to afford any distractions) to focus. One of my favorite times in school was the summer I spent living my myself on ~$450/month. I paid rent, utilities, gas and put $20-40/wk aside for food. The rest went into the bank. I spent all my time at the library or the studio and ramped up my work for nearly three months.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>2011 Kickoff</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/15/kickoff"/>
   <updated>2011-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/15/kickoff</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After finishing the last music project, I was starting off the year wallowing with a lack of plans. From all the time spent in school, I seem to work better with a plan that involves projects ramping up and down. Without it, it just feels like one endless stream of days and I end up like David Byrne, &amp;#8220;My god, how did I get here?&amp;#8221;. I need the list of tasks checked off and projects complete to assure myself that I&amp;#8217;m not wasting time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting my crap together generally involves one very long text file of all the books I want to read and projects I want to do. These get pared down into reasonable tasks that go into whatever I&amp;#8217;m using to track work (so for &amp;#8216;Things.app&amp;#8217; has held that place for two years, but I&amp;#8217;m positive I&amp;#8217;ll just go back to a todo.txt).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was good to have a bit of break over the holidays and spend time with Jen. I feel like I got a nice bit of inertia going with the last music project and I to take advantage of that and work on some projects that I need a lot more motivation to get myself to do.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>X-mas Vacation 2010</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/02/xmas-break-2010"/>
   <updated>2011-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/02/xmas-break-2010</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trip to Indianapolis to hit bookstores and see downtown. Decent hotel right on the circle. We checked out the Kurt Vonnegut Memorial Library which had some great photos of Vonnegut. We also did a quick drive-by of the Fountain Square district which is probably much better nicer when it&amp;#8217;s warm enough to actually walk around.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Trip to Louisville to visit the brother. We hit a few bookstores and ate very well as always.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Lots of cooking: rib-eye steaks, deep dish pizza, spaghetti sauce, shoulder roast, stroganoff. Lots of heavy, cold-weather comfort foods.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Checked out the Chicago Botanical Gardens to test out some camera stuff.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Got Jen to sit through Season One of The Wire. It&amp;#8217;s easy to forget just how tremendous that show is.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Spent too many hours finishing up the last music project and zero hours thinking about work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>2010 review</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/02/review2010"/>
   <updated>2011-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/02/review2010</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t reach my &amp;#8216;Road to 400 Goals&amp;#8217; but I did end the year with a personal record for deadlift and weighted in 10 lbs lighter by the end of the year. Most of my lifts remained the same or went up, so I&amp;#8217;m happy to have retained muscle mass while loosing a bit of extra weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;#8217;ve been doing so much heavy work, I&amp;#8217;m going to start off the year with a couple months of high-rep, low-weight work with an emphasis on getting my heart rate up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;51 books this year, not all of them winners, but as I get older I&amp;#8217;m getting better at cutting out the garbage quicker. It&amp;#8217;s easy to tell the time of year based on what I&amp;#8217;m reading, more serious work during the start/end of the year and light stuff over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='top_ten_books'&gt;Top Ten Books:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything Matters – Ron Currie, Jr.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Although of Course You End Up Becoming Yourself: A Road Trip With David Foster Wallace – David Lipsky&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;After the Workshop – John McNally&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Switch – Chip &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Drive – Daniel Pink&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Listen to This - Alex Ross&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Creative Writers Survival Guide – John McNally&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Big Short - Michael Lewis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Where Good Ideas Come From - Steven Johnson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Guide to the Good Life - William Irvin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id='other_music_stuff_i_remember_listening_to_a_whole_bunch_to_in_2010'&gt;Other music stuff I remember listening to a whole bunch to in 2010:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jónsi - Go&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Janelle Monáe - The ArchAndroid&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Broken Social Scene - Forgiveness Rock Record&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Bad Plus - Never Stop&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The National - High Violet&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Raphael Saadiq - The Way I See It&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;John Legend &amp;amp; The Roots - Wake Up!&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Flying Lotus - Cosmogramma&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Christian Scott- Yesterday You Said Tomorrow&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Black Dub - S/T&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Music: Written&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put out three EPs and one full project of music this year, (about 108 minutes of sound). I&amp;#8217;m pretty happy with the output and I see a lot of change and progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Next Year:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already have a reading list about 15 items deep. For music I want to get back into Max/MSP and build more interactive processing in Reaktor. I also have a pile of Abersold jazz books that I should spend more time with. The older I get the more I feel a need to dig deeper into harmony.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DT8</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/02/dt8"/>
   <updated>2011-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2011/01/02/dt8</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I finished &lt;a href='http://www.mjladd.com/music'&gt;DT8&lt;/a&gt; over vacation. It was written in fits and starts over the last three/four months in quick chunks whenever I could grab some time. Mostly written in the early morning hours when I couldn&amp;#8217;t sleep (2:30-5am mostly and a few rushed lunch hours at home).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I spend the cash and starting adding live instruments to the recordings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Notes Software: Logic 9, Komplete 7, Reason (only for the track Recessed), Axon, Tattoo, ValhallaShimmer Hardware: Pod X3, Shure Beta 58, Gretsch Electromatic G5120, Taylor 114ce, Ovation Celebrity, Kamouraska Concert, Oxygen 49&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2010</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2010/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2010-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2010/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2010&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive - Daniel Pink&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Toy Collector - James Gunn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;After the Workshop - John McNally&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Spanking the Donkey - Matt Taibbi&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Anathem - Neil Stephenson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Astonishing Life of Octavian Nothing Vol 1 - M. T. Anderson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Smells Like Dead Elephants - Matt Taibbi&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Switch - Chip &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Logic of Life - Tim Harford&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You Remind Me of Me - Dan Chaon&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Next - James Hynes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo - Stieg Larsson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Checklist Manifesto - Atul Gawande&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Although of Course You End Up Becoming Yourself: A Road Trip With David Foster Wallace - David Lipsky&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Serious Barbecue - Adam Perry Lang&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Feed - MT Anderson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Girl Who Played With Fire - Stieg Larsson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Undercover Economist - Tim Harford&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Big Short - Michael Lewis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Girl With Curious Hair - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;For The Win - Cory Doctorow&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Chicago: A Biography - Domnic Pacyga&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bloom County: Vol II - Berkeley Breathed&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Girl Who Kicked the Hornet&amp;#8217;s Nest - Stieg Larsson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Florida Roadkill - Tim Dosey&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Outliers - Malcom Gladwell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Deep Blue Good-By - John D. MacDonald&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fletch - Gregory McDonald&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Accidental Billionaires - Ben Mezrich&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Woman - T. C. Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Kanban - David J. Anderson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nightmare in Pink - John D. MacDonald&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fletch Won - Gregory McDonald&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Purple Place for Dying - John D. MacDonald&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Medium Raw - Anthony Bourdain&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Web Operations - John Allspaw&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Being Geek - Michael Lopp&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Creative Writers Survival Guide - John McNally&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Star Island - Carl Hiaasen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Hunger Games - Suzanne Collins&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Moneyball - Michael Lewis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Catching Fire - Suzanne Collins&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Perfecting Sound Forever - Greg Milner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Where Good Ideas Come From - Steven Johnson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bear vs. Shark - Chris Bacholder&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Soul Minings - Daniel Lanois&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Listen to This - Alex Ross&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Considering David Foster Wallace - David Hering&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Kind of Blue - Ashley Kahn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Everything Matters - Ron Currie, Jr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Deadlift PR 405 lbs</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2010/06/28/deadlift-PR"/>
   <updated>2010-06-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2010/06/28/deadlift-PR</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hit a personal record of 405 deadlift this morning. I wasn&amp;#8217;t planning on maxing out, I had done a pretty heavy squat set two days earlier and my hamstrings were pretty sore. I had also only had about five hours of sleep, so conditions were less than ideal. I ended up feeling pretty strong after a few warm up sets and decided to go for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still want to add about 20 lbs by the end of the year and I&amp;#8217;m starting to feel optimistic that I may reach my goal. My grip strength has been the biggest weak point, so I&amp;#8217;ve been working a lot on my grip and lower back strength and it&amp;#8217;s been paying off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a nice adrenaline buzz when I really push myself with heavy lifts. I had the headphones going and I was able to concentrate even with a half-dozen or so ladies gabbing away right in front of me. I&amp;#8217;ve been pretty happy with my progress this summer. I haven&amp;#8217;t made a lot of big leaps, but it&amp;#8217;s been pretty steady growth with a reduced amount of pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Do very hard things, just for the sake of it.&amp;#8221; - Brian Eno&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Drive to 400</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2010/04/29/drive-to-400"/>
   <updated>2010-04-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2010/04/29/drive-to-400</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every year I come up with a crazy workout goal to keep things interesting. A couple of years ago it was going through Eric Cresey&amp;#8217;s plan and last year it was going through Dave Tate&amp;#8217;s Strong(e)r workout series (which ironically didn&amp;#8217;t leave me stronger, but I think it did improve overall physical fitness).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the totals from the last time I tested max lifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bench    335
Squat    375
Deadlift 385
        1095&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I want to push those three lifts to either hit or get close to 400 lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bench    365
Squat    405
Deadlift 425
        1195 - Just shy of the 1200 lb club&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not great numbers for a powerlifter, but not awful for a mid-30s computer geek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workout plan will be close to Wendler&amp;#8217;s 5-3-1 workout with an emphasis on assistance exercises that focus on grip strength (my biggest deadlift weakness) and lower-back health. I&amp;#8217;m codetty confident in the squat and deadlift goals, but benching makes me nervous since I don&amp;#8217;t have a spotter. Once you get 300+ lbs balanced over your throat you better be codetty confident that you&amp;#8217;ll be able to push it back up.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading progress</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2010/04/15/reading-progress"/>
   <updated>2010-04-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2010/04/15/reading-progress</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I blew through Lipsky&amp;#8217;s book on David Foster Wallace in two sittings. The times that Lipsky inserted himself or his thoughts was distracting, but it was great to dive into Wallace&amp;#8217;s head for a nice chunk of time. I was happy with how ended, it would have been easy to be morose, but instead I was left with much happier memories. I like thinking about how much DFW was enjoying the process of writing and how he was looking forward to working for a good length of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have six other books in progress right now, but I should knock out a couple of them this weekend. It&amp;#8217;s slightly nutty, but I like the mix right now. I was planning to be working on more music this month, perhaps next week when Jen will be gone for a couple of days. Right now my evenings are nothing but a White Sox game on in the background and a book in hand. Things could be much, much worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall things seem pretty solid. Made some great progress at work and got rewarded for it, and today finished off a nice project that took longer than I hoped, but it was done the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday someone at work asked how it is that I seem so happy all the time. I really didn&amp;#8217;t know how to answer that. I feel like I&amp;#8217;ve been pretty buried for awhile but it&amp;#8217;s starting to burn off like fog. It comes and goes in waves, but right now things are well. It&amp;#8217;s strange to be happy, but I never lose the feeling of other shoes dropping.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2009</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2009-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2009&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding Comics - Scott McCloud&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reinventing Comics - Scott McCloud&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Practical Ruby for System Administration - André Ben Hamou&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Maximum Strength - Eric Cressey&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Starting Strength - Mark Rippetoe&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Pulling Strings with Puppet - James Turnbull&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s Play Doctor - Mark Leyer and Billy Goldberg&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Emergency - Neil Strauss&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Moneyball - Michael Lewis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Art of Capacity Planing - John Allspaw&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The War of Art - Steven Pressfield&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Pixar Touch - David Price&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Made to Stick - Chip Heath and Dan Heath&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Spaceman Blues - Brian Francis Slattery&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Design of Everyday Things - Don Norman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Linked - Albert-Laszlo Barabasi&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Sheltering Sky - Paul Bowles&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Task of This Translator - Todd Hasak-Lowy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Confidential - Anthony Bourdain&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Strain - Guillermo Del Toro &amp;amp; Chris Hogan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Black Swan - Nassim Nicholas Taleb&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Scarecrow - Michael Connelly&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sleeping With the Devil - Robert Baer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Infinite Jest - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Magicians - Lev Grossman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Infinite Jest: A Reader&amp;#8217;s Guide - Stephen Burn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Brief Interviews With Hideous Men - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Graveyard Book - Neil Gaiman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Rosencrantz and Guildenstern are Dead - Tom Stoppard&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Superfreakonomics - Levitt &amp;amp; Dubner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Complete Game - Ron Darling&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Eating the Dinosaur - Chuck Klosterman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Great Derangement - Matt Taibbi&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Up in the Air - Walter Kirn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Book of Basketball - Bill Simmons&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Netherland - Joseph O&amp;#8217;Neill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>W15D1</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/12/07/w15d1"/>
   <updated>2009-12-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/12/07/w15d1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is supposed to a be complete week off from lifting. After taking the weekend off, I had to get in and do something. I&amp;#8217;m going to focus on getting in some cardio and doing more ab work and recovery work on my shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent nearly 30 hrs over the extended weekend working on music. I finally got around to reading and watching a bunch of tutorials for the Native Instruments software and have a better handle on things like Kore2 and Reaktor. I need to but more time aside to crafting sounds, but lately I&amp;#8217;ve been far more interested in creating new music rather than sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did finish one tune and worked another one from start to finish. I&amp;#8217;m hoping to get another EP finished by the end of January. It&amp;#8217;ll be more soul &amp;amp; funk influenced. Since I never got to play in a funk/soul band, I&amp;#8217;m taking the time to create my own virtual one. Figuring out horn lines and bass riffs has been a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a few other electronic/ambient tunes hanging around the hard drive. I need to pull those together and will probably have another CDs worth of material by spring.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DC 2009 Day 3</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/10/25/DC2009-Day-3"/>
   <updated>2009-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/10/25/DC2009-Day-3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last day and plenty to get to. We had a quick breakfast at Firehook Bakery and headed out to the Newseum. It had just opened last time we were in town but I&amp;#8217;m glad we made the trip this time. It was pretty impressive to see a half-dozen massive chunks of the Berlin Wall as well as a broken portion from the World Trade Center antenna. The 9-11 exhibit was pretty tough and we skipped the documentary. The inclusion of kleenex at the entrance to the film gave some idea that we were in no mood to check it out. The Pulitzer winning photographs were amazing to see, but again were a bit rough to take a times. I had to steady myself a few times admittedly skipped over a few. The sports photography exhibit was pretty great as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished up by returning to the American History museum which was completely packed. I was really disappointed at how many exhibits were still under construction. The popular culture exhibit was tiny, only a very small sample of what they used to have available. It was a long way to go and not see the Seinfeld puffy shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was pouring rain when we were ready to leave, so we headed back to the Metro and found a pizza place near the hotel. It was fair at best, some average wood-oven thin crust. We hung out the hotel, packed up and caught &amp;#8216;Milk&amp;#8217; on HBO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trip went fast, but it was a nice little break and great to get away. I&amp;#8217;m not sure how soon I&amp;#8217;ll be able to drag Jen back to DC, but there&amp;#8217;s still so much to see, we&amp;#8217;ll make it back again.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dc2009 Day 2</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/10/24/DC2009-Day-2"/>
   <updated>2009-10-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/10/24/DC2009-Day-2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;layout: post title: DC 2009 Day 2 category: tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;personal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;travel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='type_post'&gt;type: post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started the day with a mighty fine breakfast at Afterwards and then hit up a tourist trolley up to The National Cathedral. There&amp;#8217;s a great view of the city from the top floor and the cathedral itself is massively amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hopped back on the trolley and spend a couple hours in Georgetown. We had lunch at Billy Martin&amp;#8217;s tavern where John Kennedy proposed to Jackie. It was pretty standard tavern food, but good service and a nice, homey vibe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking around the area we hopped back on the trolley and took a long trip around the DC area and ended up at the Jefferson and Lincoln memorials. They were also worth seeing again, the Lincoln memorial is particularly inspiring. I found a great photo online of people there on election night, listening to the 2008 results on a small radio. A fine place to be on that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were pretty wiped out, so we took a short walk from the hotel to Whole Food to get a light dinner and hung out in the hotel playing cards.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DC 2009 Day 1</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/10/23/DC2009-Day-1"/>
   <updated>2009-10-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/10/23/DC2009-Day-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had a great trip out to DC, one of my favorite places on earth. Chicago has my heart, but DC pulls at my head. Such a nerd town in a non-geek way, but also has an ugly self-indulgent / self-promotional feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a quick flight out and stayed in a fancy-pants hotel just off of Dupont Circle. Lots of places to check out in Dupont including Afterwords bookstore. How can you not love a book store that is open by 7:30 am and is open all night on weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day we took the metro up to a great breakfast place named Open City (http://www.opencitydc.com/) near where we stayed last year. After breakfast we hit Arlington Cemetery which was a tough visit, lots of sadness and pride on those grounds. Hard to not get teary-eyed, particularly when seeing new graves being dug. Something like 27 graves are prepared daily. We didn&amp;#8217;t stick around to see the changing of the guard, I was already a bit on the edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We needed something a bit more lighthearted after that adventure. We headed back to the Smithsonian area to see the Museum of American History. It was closed for renovation last time we were in town and there&amp;#8217;s still a lot of work being done. Seeing the Stars and Stripes was amazing to see. I&amp;#8217;m not the most outwardly patriotic person, but you can&amp;#8217;t help feeling a sense of &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; when seeing the 30 ft tall flag in it&amp;#8217;s restored state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After checking out one floor, we headed to the American History Museum where they have a pretty hip restaurant. Mighty fine food for being served on a massive scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dragged Jen to the Hirshorn Modern Art Museum and saw the amazing &amp;#8220;Big Man&amp;#8217;. I can&amp;#8217;t describe the feeling of turning the corner and seeing the seated 7 ft tall giant with angry eyes, nude, incredibly lifelike, and seemingly ready to pounce on the nearest person. It was a great shock and fun to see others get the same shocked expression when he came into view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jen again showed amazing patience with me as we hit the Air and Space Museum which never fails to make me happy. So much amazing stuff, and so inspiring. Jen found a bench and crashed for awhile while I stared gape-mouthed at the rocket displays. Seeing &amp;#8216;The Right Stuff&amp;#8217; at a young age stuck with me and I&amp;#8217;m a sucker for anything related to the space program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed back to the Dupont area and had some lousy Mexican food at Alero&amp;#8217;s then hung around the hotel watching the Yankee&amp;#8217;s/Angles game.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Vacation Day 7 - Jul 2, 2009</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/07/02/vacation-day07"/>
   <updated>2009-07-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/07/02/vacation-day07</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Started the day by visiting the nearby Harley Davidson factory in Kansas City. I&amp;#8217;m not a bike person, but I appreciate craftsmanship and HD&amp;#8217;s ability to gardner customer loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all workers who drive HDs park in the very front of the building, there is a lot of pride in showing off their personal machines&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;HD managers and factor workers and undistinguishable, they all wear identical clothing (mostly HD gear but it is not required) the only tie I saw was worn by a visitor&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;managers and workers use the same dining area and parking&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;managers and union leaders share the same office space&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;plant workers in different cells are responsible for self-organizing and prioritizing duties&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;all workers in each cell are required to switch off every job, every worker knows every duty of the job&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;robots are cool, lots of precision robot work is performed, but hand-checked by humans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the trip to HD, we hunted down a local bookstore (Prospero&amp;#8217;s) where Jen found a couple of treasures and then walked around downtown KC. We found the library, which has a really impressive display of large books that decorate the outside of the library&amp;#8217;s parking structure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img alt='kc_06' class='alignnone size-medium wp-image-521' height='225' src='/images/kc_06-300x225.jpg' title='kc_06' width='300' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also found a neat little market and picked up some fruit. &lt;img alt='kc_09' class='alignnone size-medium wp-image-522' height='225' src='/images/kc_09-300x225.jpg' title='kc_09' width='300' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed back to the hotel and walked over to the crown center where we had a really unremarkable lunch. We took and hour or so out to check email and catch up with the outside world. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='kc_14' class='alignnone size-medium wp-image-524' height='134' src='/images/kc_14-300x134.jpg' title='kc_14' width='300' /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed out to Kauffman Stadium to see the White Sox vs the Royals. It lives in a sport&amp;#8217;s complex similar to Philadelphia where there is a baseball stadium next to a football stadium, etc .. It was really out in the middle of nowhere with nothing around it. It felt a lot more like a nice minor-league stadium. Burhle pitched a great game and we had great seats, nothing could have been better.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>IJ - Infinite Summer</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/07/02/infinite-summer"/>
   <updated>2009-07-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/07/02/infinite-summer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been participating in the infinite summer read. It&amp;#8217;s brought up a lot of memories since the first time I read Infinite Jest was on vacation ten years ago. I had just finished school and Jen and I were going to take a trip westward to visit my friend Nathan. We had little money and I needed a large book for the flight there and back. I found a British printing of IJ in the discount bin at Barnes and Noble. Something sounded familiar about the title, but I knew nothing further. It was large and looked interesting and became my vacation book on sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was intrigued by the massive size but held out to start reading, I knew that I would need something to occupy hours in the terminals as well as the six hours of flights there and back again. I knocked out a good 50% of the book that week. I have a great memory of Jen and I laying together in a Seattle hostel and reading for a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally finished the book during the first week of working at Interlochen. I pretty much pushed aside any and all social opportunities (nothing unusual about that) and did nothing but work and read IJ. I remember finishing it on a Friday evening and being so stunned that it was over that I had to get out of my dorm room and be around people for awhile, so I joined the rest of my co-workers at the local bar. I had gone into a place in my brain that I couldn&amp;#8217;t explain but I couldn&amp;#8217;t be alone either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IJ sent me down a spiral of collecting everything I could by DFW, but I haven&amp;#8217;t been able to return to IJ for years. I read the rest of his books that summer and grabbed everything I could find online. It&amp;#8217;s been a great trip getting here again, and I&amp;#8217;m really enjoying the ride again.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Vacation Day 4 - June 29, 2009</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/30/vacation-day04"/>
   <updated>2009-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/30/vacation-day04</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back on the road with a four-hour trip to St. Louis. The drive was beautiful and went through the Hoosier National Forrest. We headed directly to the Loop District since we couldn&amp;#8217;t check in for a couple of hours. We had a good lunch at Fitz&amp;#8217;s (mighty solid root-beer and creme soda on tap) and stopped at a Subterranean Books (nice bookstore with a small but decent selection). We walked around most of the Loop District as well as finding a branch of Left-Bank Books which was also small but hosted an appropriate collection of books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finding our way around the city (a lot of which looks like a bomb struck recently, pretty run-down city) we checked in to the hotel. The hotel room was nice and had a great view of the city and the stadium. We walked around the area and couldn&amp;#8217;t locate anything decent for dinner (it was down to Hooters or Hardee&amp;#8217;s), but we did see a guy try to break into two cars and shadow someone into the entrance of a condo. We holed up in the room and ordered some miserable local pizza. The special included a salad that was (no kidding) a pile of iceberg lettuce with a few strands of cheese on top. The food was a low-point in St. Louis and we spent a lot of time looking for anything better.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Vacation Day 3 - June 28, 2009</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/29/vacation-day03"/>
   <updated>2009-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/29/vacation-day03</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Got up fairly early and made the trip to Louisville. It was an easy 90 minutes on the road and we made it in time for breakfast at the North End Cafe. We hit the local Half-Price bookstores and after loading up on McAllister&amp;#8217;s sweet tea, we headed out a bit south of the city to the Zappo&amp;#8217;s outlet store. The store portion is tiny compared to the massive warehouse. It looked the length of two football fields. It&amp;#8217;s not the fancy space out in Las Vegas where you can take the tour, but Jen and Paul found a few decent deals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day was flying by so we headed back to Paul&amp;#8217;s house and started preparing for dinner: 1+ lb porterhouse steaks, grilled corn, grilled potatoes, grilled salmon and a salad. It all turned out great. After watching two episodes of &amp;#8216;Freaks &amp;amp; Geek&amp;#8217;s&amp;#8217;, we headed off to sleep with mighty-full bellies.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Vacation Day 2 - June 27, 2009</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/28/vacation-day02"/>
   <updated>2009-06-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/28/vacation-day02</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had a pretty awful night of sleep. I rarely sleep well for the first couple nights of vacation. It&amp;#8217;s a big mental adjustment trying to get my brain to relax. We slept in pretty late and then headed out to walk around the area. We headed west towards the canal walk and the state park. We caught a nice film about Alaska at the Omnimax theatre. I can watch nearly anything in Omni format. It was a good way to get out of the heat for an hour or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We grabbed a late lunch at Rock Bottom Brewery and walked around Circle Center Mall before heading back to the hotel to catch a nap before the Indian&amp;#8217;s game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had a good time at the Indians/Mudhen&amp;#8217;s game. It was a bit warm to start, but we had decent seats and it was a good crowd, not obnoxious. Victory Field is a nice park and within walking distance of the hotel. Hard to beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a good time on vacation so far. We&amp;#8217;ll see after a couple more days. I either get freaked out by the spare time or I fall into it hard and never want to go back to work.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Father's Day 2009</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/25/fathers-day"/>
   <updated>2009-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/25/fathers-day</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Father&amp;#8217;s Day 2009&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like this photo of my grandparents at the Indiana Dunes. I think it was from when they were both in high school or just out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='Gram and Grandpa Peres at Indiana Dunes' height='168' src='/images/GramGrandpaBeach-300x168.jpg' title='GramGrandpaBeach' width='300' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also from high school, my grandfather and a friend of his skipped school one day and made a road trip to Vassar College. They&amp;#8217;re wearing their Roosevelt High School sweaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='Grandpa Peres road trip to Vassar' class='size-medium wp-image-468' height='300' src='/images/GrandpaRoadtripVassar-178x300.jpg' title='GrandpaRoadtripVassar' width='178' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to remember my grandfather like this. He had a habit of working outside until tired and then taking a nap. He makes good use of a wheelbarrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='Grandpa Peres wheelbarrow nap' height='191' src='/images/GrandpaPeresWheelbarrow_21-300x191.jpg' title='GrandpaPeresWheelbarrow_2' width='300' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Vacation Day01</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/17/vacation-day01"/>
   <updated>2009-06-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/17/vacation-day01</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;layout: post title: Vacation Day 1 - June 26, 2009 category: tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;personal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;travel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='type_post'&gt;type: post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img alt='vacation_loop' class='alignnone size-medium wp-image-489' height='177' src='/images/vacation_loop-300x177.jpg' title='vacation_loop' width='300' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading out of Skokie around 6:00 am and made it through the city with no issues. It was a smooth trip until reaching Merrillville when we saw a notice about an accident on I65. The interstate was closed several miles south so we took a detour through Crown Point down state road 55 and picked up I65 again in Roselawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a bit south of Lafayette we stopped at Jen&amp;#8217;s friends house who was home working at her parents farm. I really miss the space in Indiana. I like being able to look out for miles in the distance over farmland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short visit we were back on the highway. After a stop at Max and Erma&amp;#8217;s we hit a couple of Half-Price bookstores and a children&amp;#8217;s bookstore. Good thing that we&amp;#8217;re driving this vacation since the trunk will likely be loaded with books by the time we get home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked into the hotel and watched a bit of the White Sox/Cubs game before heading out to Bazbeaux Pizza. I only went there once in college, but I was able to take the folks there when they had the family reunion in Indianapolis and everyone seemed to like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked a bit around the Mass Ave area after having a pretty decent pizza at Bazbeaux. I like the area, it&amp;#8217;s laid back and pretty casual. There&amp;#8217;s a little jazz tavern called &amp;#8216;Chatterbox&amp;#8217; here that I like. Indy&amp;#8217;s downtown area seems to be doing a bit better than it was the last time I was there, maybe three years ago. We decided to finish off the night at &amp;#8216;Dave &amp;amp; Buster&amp;#8217;s&amp;#8217;, playing air-hockey while catching the replay of the Sox game.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Vacation Day 8 - Jul 3, 2009</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/04/vacation-day08"/>
   <updated>2009-06-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/06/04/vacation-day08</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Made the trip from KC to Des Moines, IA with a fueling up stop at Cracker Barrel. DM was .. a less than thrilling stop. We hit the only bookstore we could find and grabbed some lunch at a really lousy mexican place in the capital district. We stopped at the busiest place we could find, but the food had almost no taste at all. I had a minor panic attack while walking around the area. The town felt miserable and lifeless. We were planning on catching the Iowa Cubs game that night, but the 90%+ change of rain plus the onset of my full-on panic and depression and the thought of trying to occupy another 4.5 hrs in DM before the game (that was likely to be rained out) we bailed on the town and headed home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost immediately I felt better, the idea of spending 5.5 hrs driving after a previous 3 hrs of driving was better than staying in town. The trip home was an easy drive with an Anthony Bourdain audiobook keeping us occupied.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Made to Stick</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/05/30/made-to-stick"/>
   <updated>2009-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/05/30/made-to-stick</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finished &amp;#8216;Made to Stick&amp;#8217; the other day. Solid read, like Gladwell without the arrogance but with some practicality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the way that the authors emphasis the use of &amp;#8216;the story&amp;#8217; and how much more effective and &amp;#8216;sticky&amp;#8217; concepts are when they are built into a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They break &amp;#8216;stickiness&amp;#8217; into five concepts: simple, unexpected, concrete, emotional and stories. There are definitive examples within each concept that effectively help ideas adhere become easier to recall. I&amp;#8217;ve suffered through a fair number of &amp;#8216;biz&amp;#8217; book but this one was pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This copy was from the library, but I need to pick up a copy for myself to highlight and underline and scribble over.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>dt4 progress</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/05/21/dt4-progress"/>
   <updated>2009-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/05/21/dt4-progress</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finished a track last night, &amp;#8216;Passing&amp;#8217;, three left to go. Hopefully I&amp;#8217;ll finish them this weekend and take the next week to mix and hopefully master next weekend. I&amp;#8217;m listening to some of the tracks that I finished months ago and I&amp;#8217;m reasonably happy with them. I&amp;#8217;m trying some new ideas and they have a different sound than the last project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like getting up early to get work done but sometimes at night when I&amp;#8217;m on a roll I start to get some anxiety about getting enough sleep to hit the gym in the morning. The workouts are the priority, they keep me sane and I guess health benefits are worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting to plan the next workout phase post vacation. It&amp;#8217;ll be good to have a week away from the gym and recover. It will also give me a chance to really beat myself up for the ten days or so prior to leaving. Workout facilities at hotels are usually pretty sparse but we usually end up doing a ton of walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First softball game tonight, should be fun. I haven&amp;#8217;t done much interacting in a non-work environment for the last 5-7 years so it&amp;#8217;s bit of a challenge to try and remember names and how normal people interact. My lousy jokes and non-sequetor references seem to get little-to-no response. I have to remind myself that not everyone has memorized every line from Arrested Development.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Pixar</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/05/20/on-pixar"/>
   <updated>2009-05-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/05/20/on-pixar</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been reading about Pixar, the company. One of my favorite notes is how much of their history lies in failure. The main computer scientist started off working in a boring CAD company, Jon Lasseter was fired from Disney, the company itself was sold by Lucas to Jobs who then tried to sell of parts of it for years. Even when &amp;#8216;Toy Story&amp;#8217; was set to be released, Mattel and Hasbro couldn&amp;#8217;t be bothered to distribute toys (Disney&amp;#8217;s primary concern?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script for Toy Story went through 10+ revisions and the final product is nothing like the original idea. They went through revision after revision to try to capture an effective and appealing story. Competitors such as Dreamworks rushed to compete and failed on both a technical and story level. I can&amp;#8217;t think of another film company who have had such a consistent level of quality and box-office performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember seeing &amp;#8216;Toy Story&amp;#8217; at the Dollar Cinema in Muncie and being stunned at what they were able to accomplish. I was studying music at the time and managed to get in touch with one of the sound designers at Pixar. It still remains a dream company to work for.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>gpp-w4-ssc-1, mathematica, music</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2009/05/19/gppw4scc1"/>
   <updated>2009-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2009/05/19/gppw4scc1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Day off from the gym, but Jen and I walked this morning. It was good to get up early and have a couple of hours to make some progress on a few projects before heading to work. I have a list on my desktop asking why am I not work on &amp;#8230; mathmatica, music, ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been a long, bitter and angry history with mathematics in my past but the first time I saw mathematica in college I thought it was fantastic. When the home edition became available this year I snagged it, but haven&amp;#8217;t put much time into it. I&amp;#8217;ve starting working through some of the tutorials. I really like the idea of using to plot some work issues such as capacity growth and bandwidth usage. I like the idea of forcing myself to break down the numbers and understand what we really need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started getting some music projects happening. I have about half a CD finished and four more tracks in their alpha state. I have a pretty clear path on two of them and the other two are still amorphous. I want to finish the project in the next month and then take some time to focus on &amp;#8216;big music idea&amp;#8217;. Not that it&amp;#8217;s very big, but I want to work on a piece with new sound design rather then just getting something up with stock sounds. In college I focused far more on sound design and miss that part of music.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2008</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2008-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Counting down the weeks to finish up with classes. Hopefully when finished my available reading time will increase. My plans this year include knocking out a list of books that have been gathering dust on the shelves for a few years (I&amp;#8217;m looking at you Thomas Wolfe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2008&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud Atlas - David Mitchell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Halo Effect - Phil Rosenzweig&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bridge of Sighs - Richard Russo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Gasping for Airtime - Jay Mohr&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dreaming in Code - Scott Rosenberg&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Search - John Battelle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Four Days to Glory - Mark Kreidler&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Coltrane: The Story of a Sound - Ben Ratliff&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Friday Night Lights - H.G. Bissinger&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Feast for Crows - George R. R. Martin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ultramarathon Man - Dean Karnazes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Maverick - Ricardo Semler&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Here Comes Everybody - Clay Shirky&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Art of Learning - Josh Waitzkin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bright Shiny Morning - James Frey&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Delivery Man - Joe McGinnis Jr&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Little Brother - Cory Doctorow&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tourist Season - Carl Hiaasen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Consider the Lobster - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ghosts of Chicago - John McNally&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Brain Rules - Jon Mesina&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Supposedly Fun Thing, I&amp;#8217;ll Never Do Again - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Moving to Higher Ground - Wynton Marsalis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;American Scream - Cynthia True&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Super Crunchers - Ian Ayers&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Captives - Todd Hasak-Lowy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Eat Me - Kenny Shopsin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The wisdom of Fripp</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/12/10/wisdom-of-Fripp"/>
   <updated>2008-12-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/12/10/wisdom-of-Fripp</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href='http://www.dgmlive.com/diaries.htm?entry=12714' target='_self'&gt;Robert Fripp&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;We are only ready to undertake a piece of work when we have completed that piece of work. Doing the task prepares us to do the task: we are learning on the job. So, clearly, we don’t understand how to do the job until we’ve already done it.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It always drove me nuts to attempt to estimate time for project managers.  Estimates would be tossed out with no basis in reality and I could only say &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t know.&amp;#8221; A best guess is as useful as no guess at all. Project management seems like a weak use of the term &amp;#8216;management&amp;#8217; but there&amp;#8217;s lots of pretty pictures, charts and numbers to make folks warm and fuzzy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are done when they are done.  When &lt;a href='http://www.betweenthecities.com/blog/ljr/' target='_self'&gt;Scott&lt;/a&gt; was my boss he pointed this out often and I have yet to see any contrary evidence.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tom Waits Live</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/11/06/Tom-Waits-Live"/>
   <updated>2008-11-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/11/06/Tom-Waits-Live</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a very short list of musicians that I care to see live. The live environment involves people, and people generally ruin everything. Tom Waits is on that very short list. I&amp;#8217;ve been a fan of Mr. Waits since the fall of 1992, borrowing a tape of &amp;#8216;Bone Machine&amp;#8217; from Jason Guski (sp?) and reveling in the harshness of &amp;#8216;Earth Died Screaming&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8216;Goin out West&amp;#8217; as well as the heartbreaking performances of &amp;#8216;Little Rain&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8216;Who Are You&amp;#8217;. I went on to accumulate the entire Wait&amp;#8217;s collection. Mr. Waits&amp;#8217; music has always been with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: while waiting for the show to start, we noticed a gentleman taking the stairs to the upper balcony dressed in an old suit, with a full beard and his hair wrapped in a clip to to the back of his head. I said to my brother, &amp;#8220;That&amp;#8217;s Jim James.&amp;#8221; The lead singer for My Morning Jacket was there, and we actually had better seats then he had. It took a bit of restraint to not go and become an annoying fanboy (MMJ is one of my top five bands at the moment, and their work gets better with every release).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great show and I feel very lucky to have been able to see him live. The duet performance (piano and bass) of &amp;#8216;Tom Traubert&amp;#8217;s Blues&amp;#8217; was incredible, the audience became silent and and reverential and I&amp;#8217;m sure there were a few tears shed during that tune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='setlist'&gt;Setlist&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make It Rain&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hoist that Rag&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Shore Leave&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;God&amp;#8217;s Away on Business&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All the World is Green&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;November&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Falling Down&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tom Traubert&amp;#8217;s Blues&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tango til they&amp;#8217;re Sore&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;House Where Nobody Lives&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Lucky Day&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Who&amp;#8217;s Been Talkin&amp;#8217; / Til the Money Runs Out&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Eyeball Kid&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Murder In The Red Barn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Lie to Me, Baby&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Shake it&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Circus&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Trampled Rose&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Get Behind The Mule&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It Rains on Me&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Goin Out West&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='encore'&gt;Encore&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day After Tomorrow&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t Go Into That Barn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Studs and Himself</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/10/31/Studs-and-Himself"/>
   <updated>2008-10-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/10/31/Studs-and-Himself</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;pubDate&gt;Fri, 31 Oct 2008 21:32:53 +0000&lt;/pubDate&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the passing of Studs Terkel and DFW last month, Mr. Terkel&amp;#8217;s quote is very apt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;With optimism, you look upon the sunny side of things. People say, &amp;#8216;Studs, you&amp;#8217;re an optimist.&amp;#8217; I never said I was an optimist. I have hope because what&amp;#8217;s the alternative to hope? Despair? If you have despair, you might as well put your head in the oven.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>WWs04e01</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/10/25/WWs04e01"/>
   <updated>2008-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/10/25/WWs04e01</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;pubDate&gt;Sat, 25 Oct 2008 18:03:09 +0000&lt;/pubDate&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making my way through the West Wing DVDs. The end of episode 1 season 4:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;If our job teaches us anything, it&amp;#8217;s that we don&amp;#8217;t know what the next President&amp;#8217;s gonna face. And if we choose someone with vision, someone with guts, someone with gravitas, who&amp;#8217;s connected to other people&amp;#8217;s lives, and cares about making them better&amp;#8230; if we choose someone to inspire us, then we&amp;#8217;ll be able to face what comes our way and achieve things&amp;#8230; we can&amp;#8217;t imagine yet. Instead of telling people who&amp;#8217;s the most qualified, instead of telling people who&amp;#8217;s got the better ideas, let&amp;#8217;s make it obvious.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DFW</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/09/14/dfw"/>
   <updated>2008-09-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/09/14/dfw</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;pubDate&gt;Sun, 14 Sep 2008 03:29:56 +0000&lt;/pubDate&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite writer commited suicide &lt;a href='http://www.nytimes.com/aponline/books/AP-Obit-Wallace.html'&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt;. Looking at my bookshelves there&amp;#8217;s not many left. Bukowski,  Burroughs and Carver are long gone, Selby and Thompson much more recent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside with his commencement &lt;a href='http://www.marginalia.org/dfw_kenyon_commencement.html'&gt;address&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ll be re-reading my favorite short story by him as well, &amp;#8216;Good Old Neon&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Good Old Neon - excerpt)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is that dying isn&amp;#8217;t bad, but it takes forever. And that forever is no time at all. I know that sounds like a contradiction, or maybe just wordplay. What it really is, it turns out, is a matter of perspective. The big picture, as they say, in which the fact is that this whole seemingly endless back-and-forth between us has come and gone and come again in the very same instant that Fern stirs a boiling pot for dinner, and your stepfather packs some pipe tobacco down with his thumb, and Angela Mead uses an ingenious little catalogue tool to roll cat hair off her blouse, and Melissa Betts inhales to respond to something she thinks her husband just said, and David Wallace blinks in the midst of idly scanning class photos from his 1980 Aurora West H.S. yearbook and seeing my photo and trying, through the tiny little keyhold of himself, to imagine what all must have happened to lead up to my death in the fiery single-car accident he&amp;#8217;d read about in 1991, like what sorts of pain or problems might have driven the guy to get in his electric-blue Corvette and try to drive with all that O.T.C. medication in his bloodstream David Wallace happening to have a huge and totally unorganizable set of inner thoughts, feelings, memories and impressions of this little photo&amp;#8217;s guy a year ahead of him in school with the seemingly almost neon aura around him all the time of scholastic and athletic excellence and popularity and success with the ladies, as well as of every last cutting remark or even tiny disgusted gesture or expression on this guy&amp;#8217;s part whenever David Wallace struck out looking in Legion ball or said something lame at a party, and of how impressive and authentically at ease in the world the guy always seemed, like an actual living person instead of the dithering, pathetically self-conscious outline or ghost of a person David Wallace knew himself back then to be. Verily a fair-haried, fast-track guy, whom in the very best human tradition David Wallace had back then imagined as happy and unreflective and wholly unhaunted by voices telling him that there was something deeply wrong with him that wasn&amp;#8217;t wrong with anybody else and that he had to spend all of his time and energy trying to figure out what to do and say in order to impersonate an even marginally normal or acceptable U.S. male, all this stuff clanging around in David Wallace &amp;#8216;81&amp;#8217;s head every second and moving so fast that he never got a chance to catch hold and try to fight or argue against it or even really feel it except as a knot in his stomach as he stood in his real parents&amp;#8217; kitchen ironing his uniform and thinking of all the ways he could screw up and strike out looking or drop balls out in right and reveal his true pathetic essence in front of this .418 hitter and his witchily pretty sister and everyone else in the audience in lawn chairs in the grass along the sides of the Legion field (all of whom already probably saw through the sham from the outset anyway, he was pretty sure) in other words David Wallace trying, if only in the second his lids are down, to somehow reconcile what this luminous guy had seemed like from the outside with whatever on the interior must have driven him to kill himself in such a dramatic and doubtlessly painful way with David Wallace also fully aware that the cliche that you can&amp;#8217;t ever truly know what&amp;#8217;s going on inside somebody else is hoary and insipid and yet at the same time trying very conciously to prohibit that awareness from mocking the attempt or sending the whole line of thought into the sort of inbent spiral that keeps you from ever getting anywhere (considerable time having passed since 1981, of course, and David Wallace having emerged from years of literally indescribable war against himself with quite a bit more firepower than he&amp;#8217;d had at Aurora West), the realer, more enduring and sentimental part of him commanding that other part to be silent as if looking it levelly in the eye and saying, almost aloud, &amp;#8216;Not another word.&amp;#8217;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Brad Bird quote</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/07/22/Brad-Bird"/>
   <updated>2008-07-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/07/22/Brad-Bird</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just got back from vacation and trying to catch up on email, rss feeds and laundry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Came across this quote yesterday that I really liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In my experience, the thing that has the most significant impact on a movie’s budget–but never shows up in a budget–is morale. If you have low morale, for every $1 you spend, you get about 25 cents of value. If you have high morale, for every $1 you spend, you get about $3 of value. Companies should pay much more attention to morale.”&lt;/em&gt; - Brad Bird&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Inspiration</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/06/28/inspiration"/>
   <updated>2008-06-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/06/28/inspiration</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously inspiring and ego damaging to read about someone (&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cameron_Sinclair'&gt;Cameron Sinclair&lt;/a&gt;) my own age doing such amazing work. His Ted &lt;a href='http://www.ted.com/tedtalks/tedtalksplayer.cfm?key=c_sinclair'&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; is well worth watching. People like him really make me ask why I am wasting my life and how can I move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as the Ted stuff can be accused of being elitist, there is some goddamned inspiring work.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>MSIT Graduation Jun 20 2008</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/06/27/msit-graduation"/>
   <updated>2008-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/06/27/msit-graduation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last Friday I graduated from the &lt;a href='http://infotech.northwestern.edu'&gt;MSIT&lt;/a&gt; program at Northwestern. It&amp;#8217;s took too years and way too much money, but it&amp;#8217;s over. It certainly wasn&amp;#8217;t every I hoped for, but it&amp;#8217;s over. Coming from a tiny town in Indiana, I never thought I would ever graduate from any university of any renown (BM and MM from Ball State). It was a personal success in that regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now have my Saturdays free, and am looking forward to taking my first vacation in several years.  Having your weekends halved, and many nights spent doing homework left for very little free time.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day in Chicago</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/06/20/day-in-Chicago"/>
   <updated>2008-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/06/20/day-in-Chicago</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had some personal days to use, so Jen and I headed downtown today. Had a fantastic day, gorgeous weather, good food, no complaints at all. Had a great breakfast at &amp;#8216;Orange&amp;#8217;: fruit sushi, cinnamon roll pancakes, and fruit kabob.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked out the Apple Store on Michigan Ave, and walked down to Millenium Park and caught part of an orchestra rehearsal. It was a great day off, something I haven&amp;#8217;t had since November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow the family is coming up for graduation and the brother will be staying around for another couple of days. I&amp;#8217;m assuming a fair amount of pizza will be consumed, including a possible visit to pizza fest in Lincoln Park.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Packed Up</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/06/12/packed-up"/>
   <updated>2008-06-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/06/12/packed-up</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Heading out in the morning for the big east coast trip. Three/Four cities in one week (Boston, DC, Baltimore, Philadelphia). It is the first vacation we&amp;#8217;ve been able to take in nearly three years, so I&amp;#8217;m pretty excited. It&amp;#8217;ll be nice to be able to visit with friends as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worse thing about AM flights is that I can never sleep well. I&amp;#8217;ll probably end up waking up 5-6 times and being unable to sleep on the flight. The iphone is loaded with enough music, tv shows, and Ted presentations to keep me occupied, along with a 600 page Hunter S. Thompson book (&amp;#8216;72 Campaign, to keep in the spirit of visiting DC).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Simplify</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/04/23/simplify"/>
   <updated>2008-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/04/23/simplify</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thinking of how to keep my life in sync b/w work and home. Normally everything lives in a DevonThink database so all of my research is with me all the time. I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to put more of my day-to-day notes and calendar stuff into .txt files and run the risk of forgetting to copy things back and forth to my USB key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I really want is for my /home to live on my iPod, so I can plug in and work, but that hasn&amp;#8217;t happened yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m looking into either using github or projectlocker and write a script to  sync up when I log off/on multiple workstations. If my handwriting wasn&amp;#8217;t so slow (and illegible), I could probably go back to living in a notebook.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Baby Huey</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/04/06/baby-huey"/>
   <updated>2008-04-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/04/06/baby-huey</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been listening to a lot of funk and soul music. I like digging up artists from obscure areas of the US where I never imagined funk to emerge. Listening to &amp;#8216;The Baby Huey Story: The Living Legend &amp;#8217; right now. Nice touch, James &amp;#8220;Baby Huey&amp;#8221; Rame was born in Richmond, IN (which if I remember correctly became the home for one of the Graham Brothers) and moved to Chicago at nineteen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baby Huey was 400 pounds of soul, with a great voice and apparently impressive stage presence. The horn lines, particularly in &amp;#8216;Listen to Me&amp;#8217;, remind me of some horn work from Frank Zappa. The cover of &amp;#8216;A Change is Gonna Come&amp;#8217; is probably unnecessary, it&amp;#8217;s pretty hard to match the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been collecting a big list of funk/soul compilations lately and have another 15 or so queued up for purchase.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Stapled to the bone</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/03/23/stapled-to-the-bone"/>
   <updated>2008-03-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/03/23/stapled-to-the-bone</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight I&amp;#8217;ve been flipping between the NCAA basketball playoffs and the NCAA wrestling championship.  College wrestling gets little television time, but I&amp;#8217;ve never seen any other athletes work as hard as wrestlers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just saw a wrestler named Mark Perry from the University of Iowa (which has a tremendous history of success at the college level, including 21 national championships since 1975) wresting at 165 lbs. Five weeks out of surgery which involved his meniscus being stapled to his bone, Perry had his knee severely hyper-extended half-way through the second period of his match. He was in enough pain to cause him to crawl off the mat. With his leg failing beneath his own body weight, he held out to win the match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a tremendous amount of respect for wrestlers. The seven minutes on the mat is completely exhausting, and like many non-spotlight sports, they get little attention. I can&amp;#8217;t think of another sport that requires as much effort to maintain appropriate weight (perhaps gymnastics?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I enjoy the excitement and energy of the basketball championships, there is something more inspiring to me to see an individual winning or losing on their own.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Tiny Victory</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/03/01/a-tiny-victory"/>
   <updated>2008-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/03/01/a-tiny-victory</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;layout: post title: A tiny victory category: tags: - personal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='type_post'&gt;type: post&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had a fantastic evening yesterday. Got out of work and picked up a quick meal before heading out to the library. It was great to have a couple of hours to simply think and knock out some work. I finished a paper for school and had some time to think and decompress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Counting down the weeks of class (T-13) and can&amp;#8217;t wait to be done. It certainly wasn&amp;#8217;t what I hoped it would be, but it was a gamble like anything else, we&amp;#8217;ll see how it pays off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the great night, I faced a work day of pounding my head with seemingly impossible problems of integrating Active Directory with a current ldap authentication plan. The current setup is riddled with enough security issues to keep me awake at night if I let myself think too much about it. Every bit of research turns up another block so research progress came up with a lot of options, and many of them troublesome. I feel like I&amp;#8217;m starting to get an idea of what will need to be done, but the how is elusive. I&amp;#8217;m very happy to work where I work and the challenges are great. I just have to keep focused on months down the line and how to get things to fall into place.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bridge Of Sighs</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/01/29/bridge-of-sighs"/>
   <updated>2008-01-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/01/29/bridge-of-sighs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;layout: post title: Bridge of Sighs category: tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;personal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reading&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='type_post'&gt;type: post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finished &amp;#8216;Bridge of Sighs&amp;#8217; last night when I should have been working on homework.  For the second Russo novel in a row, I wish I stopped reading before the last 50 pages. As in &amp;#8216;Empire Falls&amp;#8217; the cliches stand out to the point of distraction. When the &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magical_Negro'&gt;Magical Negro&lt;/a&gt; appears I wanted to throw the book away. In &amp;#8216;Empire Falls&amp;#8217;, the school shooting made me mad enough to mark the page to know when to stop when I get the time to re-read it. Two great books that made me want to rip out 50 pages of them and put them back on the shelf.   &amp;#8217;Bridge&amp;#8217; was absolutely fantastic up to the appearance of &amp;#8216;Miss Cleo&amp;#8217; and I&amp;#8217;m frustrated that I allow that small part to soil the rest of the book.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Distraction</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/01/20/distraction"/>
   <updated>2008-01-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/01/20/distraction</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every once in awhile I get the urge to dive back into music, to load up the laptop with music software and start being creative again. I blame it on two things; feeling like what I do now is not creative, and my brain trying to keep me from doing what I should be doing (in this case, homework).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since school has turned into a somewhat useless exercise in going through the motions, my brain is trying to save itself from boredom. Calculating the traffic intensity of base stations is not all that thrilling. The pathetic part is that the music I used to create doesn&amp;#8217;t even interest me anymore. Knowing how simple it is to create most music has taking away alot of the excitement I used to have. What used to really interest me was the development of new sounds and experimenting with audio synthesis. There&amp;#8217;s been hardly anything new in that area for at least 10 years, and the same sounds and processes are pretty deadening. I suppose most of the work has moved onto subtle improvements rather than ground-breaking experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lunchtime Reading</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/01/18/lunchtime-reading"/>
   <updated>2008-01-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/01/18/lunchtime-reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to spend my lunch hours at work reading. It&amp;#8217;s a nice break from IT and gives me time to use the part of my brain that isn&amp;#8217;t swearing at servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother passed along a section of Richard Russo&amp;#8217;s newest book a few weeks ago, and I just ran across it today. Pages 123-125 captures the most accurate telling of adolescence that I&amp;#8217;ve ever read. I couldn&amp;#8217;t get that section out of my head and went back to re-read it at least three times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;We shared, all of us, a powerful sense that what was at stake on those crowded stairs was nothing less than the rest of our lives, that our every move in that gymnasium had an unimaginable significance, that we were being watched, judged, elected, or damned.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>TB - Tale of God's Will</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2008/01/08/Tale-of-Gods-Will"/>
   <updated>2008-01-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2008/01/08/Tale-of-Gods-Will</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Terence Blanchard&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;A Tale of God&amp;#8217;s Will&amp;#8217; is my favorite jazz recording of last year, and probably in my top five music purchases as well.  It reminds me of Pat Metheny&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Secret Story&amp;#8217; in it&amp;#8217;s scope and ambition. Its difficult to marry the jazz ethos alongside a symphonic score, but Blanchard does an amazing job, without becoming sappy or overdone. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2007</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2007/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2007-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2007/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:I had originally planned on taking this year to focus on only reading a few select large books (Infinite Jest, Underworld, etc..) but there&amp;#8217;s just too much out there I want to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2007&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk Talk - T. C. Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Children&amp;#8217;s Hospital - Chris Adrian&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Sleeping Dragon - Joel Rosenberg&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Road - Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Immortal Game - David Shenk&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sex, Drugs, and Coco Puffs - Chuck Klosterman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bad Haircuts - Tom Perrotta&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Killing Yourself to Live - Chuck Klosterman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fargo Rock City - Chuck Klosterman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Joe College - Tom Perrotta&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;IV - Chuck Klosterman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;America&amp;#8217;s Report Card - John McNally&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Fistfull of Fig Newtons - Jean Shepherd&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Freakonomics - Steven Levit &amp;#38; Stephen Dubner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;When I Was a Loser - Ed. John McNally&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The War of Art - Steven Pressfield&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Founders at Work - Jessica Livingston&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Dull Roar - Henry Rollins&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Parasite Rex - Carl Zimmer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nature Girl - Carl Hiaasen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Less Than Zero - Bret Easton Ellis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Little Children - Tom Perrotta&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Happy Endings - Jim Norton&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tapping the Source - Kem Numm&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows - J. K. Rowling&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Youth in Revolt - C. D. Payne&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Population 487 - Michael Perry&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Managing Humans - Michael Lopp&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ugly Americans - Ben Mezrich&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bringing Down the House - Ben Mezrich&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Rigged - Ben Mezrich&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Rest is Noise - Alex Ross&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Middlesex- Jeffery Eugenides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Over There</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2007/10/11/over-there"/>
   <updated>2007-10-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2007/10/11/over-there</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last night at home with Jen, we had the Jazz cable music channel on while she was reading and I was working on the laptop. I heard &amp;#8220;Over There&amp;#8221; by Terence Blanchard and was stunned. I sat starting and the awful slideshow displayed by the channel and listened to the 7+ minute tune without moving. It&amp;#8217;s rare that I hear much newer Jazz that hits me like this did. Afterwards, it was a quick visit to the Amazon MP3 store and I was all set. I&amp;#8217;ve listened to the entire project &amp;#8220;A Tale of God&amp;#8217;s Will (Requiem for Katrina)&amp;#8221; twice now and the tune &amp;#8220;Over There&amp;#8221; at least six times. It&amp;#8217;s an amazing work, and I&amp;#8217;m lucky that I came across it. I&amp;#8217;ve been too busy with work and school to keep up with much new music, and most of my time listening to Jazz involves making my way through a hundred or so John Coltrane projects and bootlegs.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DFW2</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2007/09/15/dfw2"/>
   <updated>2007-09-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2007/09/15/dfw2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Infinite Jest was a title that rang in my head for some reason, so I picked up the $5 British pressing paperback at Barne&amp;#8217;s and Noble while looking for something of decent length to read on my first post-college vacation in spring of 1999. On the flight from Indianapolis to Seattle (via Detroit) I opened the massive novel and dived in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite memories of the trip was lying in the hostel in downtown Seattle and reading Infinite Jest. Just out of college and truly broke, there wasn&amp;#8217;t a lot of night-time entertainment available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember talking about David Foster Wallace with my friend Nathan when we stayed at his apartment where I read the first story of &amp;#8216;A Supposedly Fun Thing I&amp;#8217;ll Never Do Again&amp;#8217; and I was taken. The rest of the vacation involved hunting through multiple used-book stores to purchase the rest of his work. I spend the rest of the summer reading everything I could find by him, finally finishing IJ at the music camp I worked at that year. I spend a Friday evening in the dorm room while the rest of the team went out drinking.  After finishing the book, I had to get out and socialize, albiet briefly, just to get out of my own head for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember reading &amp;#8216;The Girl With Curious Hair&amp;#8217; on the beach at Interlochen and finally ordering &amp;#8216;Brief Interviews with Hideous Men&amp;#8217; from Amazon when I had nothing left to consume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading DFW made my brain echo in a funny but enjoyable way. The struggle and reach to comprehend was always worth the effort. It reminded me of the first time I heard Stravinsky and the opening bassoon of &amp;#8216;The Rite of Spring&amp;#8217; ran through my head like warm water. Something about it just fit my chemistry and made me care more about what sounds I heard (and with DFW, what words I read).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I was rereading &amp;#8216;Consider the Lobster&amp;#8217; and surfing around to try and see if any new work was coming out. I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to revisiting his work in the near future. The unfortunate passage is going to make the going a bit darker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;This is water. This is water.&amp;#8221; - DFW&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Population 485 - Michael Perry</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2007/09/12/population-485"/>
   <updated>2007-09-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2007/09/12/population-485</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Started reading this last night, and it immediately took my back to my hometown. Michael has returned to his hometown and becomes a volunteer fireman. It&amp;#8217;s a book that I wish I had an afternoon to lose myself in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit: I really like this line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Working-class prejudice never quite shakes the idea of art as frivolity, and frivolity has pink-palms.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming from a small town, this was always something rolling around in my head while I was studying music. How useless it would seem at times.  I still have similar feelings about IT, questioning if I should be doing something that may have a more positive impact.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2006</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2006-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary: Since I had accumulated a huge backlog of unread books, I had planned out my reading for the entire year. A minimum of a book a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: I got dragged down by a couple of slow books (I&amp;#8217;m looking at you Thomas Friedman) and school took up a lot of time, I missed by goal by about 14 books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2006&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time Management for System Administrators - Thomas Limoncelli&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Clash of Kings - George R. R. Martin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Consider the Lobster - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance - Robert Pirsig&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Chaos - James Gleick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Vision Quest - Terry Davis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;An Unfinished Season - Ward Just&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Short History of Nearly Everything - Bill Bryson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The One Minute Manger - Kenneth Blanchard&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;21 Dog Years - Mike Daisey&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;What Your CEO Wants You to Know - Ram Charam&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Slack - Tom DeMarco&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Staggerford - Jon Hassler&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fortress of Solitude - Jonathan Lethem&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Inside Delta Force - Eric L. Haney&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Protect Your Windows Network - Jesper M. Johansson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The World is Flat - Thomas Friedman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mind Performance Hacks - Ron Hale-Evans&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Spunk &amp;amp; Bite - Arthur Plotnik&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Razor&amp;#8217;s Edge - W. Somerset Maugham&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Nasty Bits - Anthony Bourdain&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Project X - Jim Shepard&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Men and Cartoons - Jonathan Lethem&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Indecision - Ben Kunkel&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;White Teeth - Zadie Smith&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;America&amp;#8217;s Report Card - John McNally&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mind Wide Open - Stephen Johnson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nightwatch - Sergei Lukyanenko&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mysteries of Pittsburgh - Michael Chabon&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tooth and Claw - T.C. Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Wanda Hickey&amp;#8217;s Night of Golden Memories - Jean Shepherd&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;American Skin - Don DeGrazia&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sideways - Rex Pickett&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;This Boy&amp;#8217;s Life - Tobias Wolff&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Why Do Me Fall Asleep After Sex - Mark Leyner and Billy Goldberg&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Everything Bad is Good for You - Steven Johnson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Wilco: Learning How to Die - Gret Kot&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Storm of Swords - George R. R. Martin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Milwaukee</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/10/03/Milwaukee"/>
   <updated>2006-10-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/10/03/Milwaukee</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since Jen had Monday off, we headed up to Milwaukee to get a short little vacation, pretty much the only time off that we&amp;#8217;ll both have. Jen picked me up after class on Saturday and we headed northward. The trip went well until we got near downtown and the expressway just ended. After a futile attempt to find the hotel and being transferred to the wrong number from information, we managed to find our way to the lovely Ambassador Hotel. The design was art-deco and the room provided a personal DVD player and internet access. There was also an excellent coffee shop (Caffe Deco) in the hotel that served Alterra coffee, which was fantastic. There was a surprising number of different coffee places, and I only remember seeing a single Starbucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After checking out the room we asked the desk person for a dining recommendation. She mentioned a place that was &amp;#8216;two blocks away&amp;#8217;. Apparently two blocks is more like 10-12. After walking around the area for a good hour, we grabbed the car and made our way downtown. Since 90% of the city is under construction, it took awhile to find parking. We stumbled into some sort of Octoberfest (beer, fire-eaters, and accordians!!) and finally found a mediocre Thai restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the majority of the next day downtown (after spending 45 minutes trying to go the three miles to the art museum, again the expressway ended, but this time going in the opposite direction). The weather was fantastic and I took a metric crapload of photos of the museum. We got another dining recommendation (two blocks again? more like seven) and after stuffing down some fantastic pretzels, we headed back to the car. The fun part of the day was attempting to get out of the parking garage. Due to construction, two of the three exits from the parking garage were closed and there was only one gate open to take money. It took about 30 minutes just to get out of the garage. Jen was pretty wiped out after hauling her gimp foot around all day so she crashed for a couple of hours while I got caught up with some work online. We headed out to the local casino for and hour or so, but the choking cigarettes sent us home with few winnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For dinner we just grabbed some sandwiches from a small place near Marquette and hung out in the room and watched a couple of episodes of Battlestar Galactica.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day started off with more Altera coffee and a trip to the Mitchell Park Domes before heading back toward Chicago. We made a quick stop at the Mars Cheese Castle to grab some gifts of cheese and summer sausage. The rest of the trip home was trouble-free. It was good to get away for a couple of weeks. With school going on, it&amp;#8217;s not likely that we&amp;#8217;ll have much in the way of vacation time for the next couple of years. Hopefully we&amp;#8217;ll get a few more weekend trips like this in.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>another early AM</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/09/24/another-early-am"/>
   <updated>2006-09-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/09/24/another-early-am</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;6:00 AM and I&amp;#8217;ve been up for a few hours already. Watching a video by Lyle Lovett on YouTube (She&amp;#8217;s Already Made Up Her Mind). I remember seeing this video on a tiny little black and white TV at my parents old house. It made me a huge fan of Lovett&amp;#8217;s music, and I&amp;#8217;ve been lucky enough to see him several times live and even assisted with the sound for a performance while I was at the Interlochen Music Camp (Summer of 1999). The internet can be such a mindtrip. I just stuck in the keyword &amp;#8216;Interlochen&amp;#8217; into flickr, and found photos of the recording studios were I spent the majority of my time that summer. Seven years ago, seems like a lifetime, and the person who I was then is a stranger to myself now. As much as I love music, I don&amp;#8217;t miss hauling racks of gear around to record lousy music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this all got triggered by a yahoo news story about an artist named Chris Smither. During the summer at Interlochen I was asked to do live sound for him in a small theatre in some little arty community in northern Michigan. I remember hauling all the equipment in and out of the place myself and thinking that I was pretty much tired of being a roady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad plus have a great list of tracks in memory of John Coltrane&amp;#8217;s birthday. So I have a new playlist ready to go for my afternoon trip to the library. I&amp;#8217;ve been listening to Coltrane for about 17 years, and I always find something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battery is just about dead on the laptop and gym will open in another 45 minutes. Time to get moving.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quiet Weekend</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/04/02/quiet-weekend"/>
   <updated>2006-04-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/04/02/quiet-weekend</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pretty good weekend, good to get away from thinking about work. With system administration, there&amp;#8217;s always the worry that something will break, and I&amp;#8217;ll miss an alert, and work will be a nightmare the moment I walk in. Being a small company, every little thing falls into either my lap, or James&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phil came by and we got some decent Asian food and hung out for a bit playing cards. I threw &amp;#8216;Clerks&amp;#8217; on the DVD player for background noise. I hadn&amp;#8217;t seen it in awhile, but it brought back a few memories. I was lucky enough to be in school at a time when independent film was getting a bit of acclaim. &amp;#8216;Pulp Fiction&amp;#8217;, &amp;#8216;Killing Zoe&amp;#8217;, and &amp;#8216;Clerks&amp;#8217; came out in 1994 when I was living in my first apartment. I was able to catch other films like &amp;#8216;Roger and Me&amp;#8217;, &amp;#8216;Slacker&amp;#8217;, and &amp;#8216;Go Fish&amp;#8217; on video. I was lucky enough to have a roommate who was a film minor and got me into films such as &amp;#8216;Man Bites Dog&amp;#8217;, &amp;#8216;Delicatessen&amp;#8217; , and the work of Kieslowski (&amp;#8216;Trois Couleurs&amp;#8217;) and Errol Morris (&amp;#8216;Thin Blue Line&amp;#8217;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel lucky since it was a time when independent music was still getting some acclaim and independent film was really taking off. It was a good time to be in school, and around folks who had similar interests.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Louisville Trip</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/03/28/Louisville-trip"/>
   <updated>2006-03-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/03/28/Louisville-trip</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Made it back from Louisville with no issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both flights were uneventful (in the best way) with no delays and the brother showed up with an airport pickup that Costanza would be proud of. Since we had skipped breakfast we made our way to Famous Dave&amp;#8217;s BBQ for an exceptionally large lunch. I settled on the chopped pork and beef brisket with some fine sweet tea. Sweet tea and BBQ are a couple of the south&amp;#8217;s saving graces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did some grocery shopping, and picked up the goods to make &amp;#8216;White Trash&amp;#8217;, an amazing crack-like snack that is impossible to stop eating. We did a bit of shopping and hit my favorite music store, Earx-Tacy. Since I tend to buy everything online, it&amp;#8217;s pretty hard to find a decent music store. They usually have something in stock that I&amp;#8217;ve been looking for. We spent the rest of the time playing some Trivial Pursuit and grabbed some pizza from one of the few semi-decent pizza places in town. As good as the BBQ is in the south, the pizza is equivalently bad. We finished the night watching &amp;#8216;Good Night and Good Luck&amp;#8217;. I&amp;#8217;ve been meaning to check out that film for awhile. It was a very solid film, the music, lighting, and performances were all very fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The food tradition was continued by heading to the Bristol Bar and Grill for their Sunday morning breakfast buffet. It&amp;#8217;s a massive amount of food and kept us content until the 2 lb. rib-eye steaks that finished off the day. We drove around the outskirts of Louisville and then headed downtown to take some photos down by the river. We stopped by the half-price bookstore and made it home to light the grill and managed to have the steaks ready by 8:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday was pretty quiet. We had some coffee and doughnuts and headed downtown to walk around and take some more pictures. The morning was pretty bright, and we got a few decent pictures before the clouds rolled in. We attempted to check out a little Italian place, Lentini&amp;#8217;s, but left without ordering food. The cook was reading a newspaper in the lobby with filthy pants and dirt stains on his hands. The waiter who showed us to our seat wore black dickies-brand pants and a stained shirt. The dishes and glassware were dirty to the point where we could scrape items off of the plates. The story goes that Frank Sinatra used to dine at this restaurant, but I have a hard time believing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We skipped out of town, and headed to the Ceasars casino, just across the state line in beautiful New Albany, Indiana. The casino was fine, if not odd how it pops out of the middle of nowhere, but the town of New Albany was frightening. It reminded me of many of the towns where I grew up. There are many beautiful old homes, but the surroundings have disintegrated as whatever industry has left town. It was sad and dismal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a rather adventurous trip back to the airport, but managed to make it in plenty of time for our flight. It was great to get out of town for a bit and visit the brother.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Days of Altman</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/03/19/days-of-altman"/>
   <updated>2006-03-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/03/19/days-of-altman</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since I was in complete bodily pain after an overindulgent workout yesterday, I spend the day catching up on a few movies and make up a bit on my 52s list. I&amp;#8217;ve hit the Altman section and made it through &amp;#8216;MASH&amp;#8217;, &amp;#8216;Nashville&amp;#8217;, and &amp;#8216;ShortCuts&amp;#8217; in the last two days. It&amp;#8217;s been really interesting seeing three Altman films in a row. He&amp;#8217;s always been one of my favorite directors and I try to catch anything that he does. It was interesting to see how his technique has evolved throughout his films. There are definite constants such as the zoom shot, overlapping conversations, and the documentary style of filming. For me it feels more like eavesdropping on a situation rather than viewing a film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The level of actors who work on his films (and generally do so at scale) is tremendous. For example &amp;#8216;ShortCuts&amp;#8217;: Andie MacDowell, Jack Lemmon, Julianne Moore, Fred Ward, Jennifer Jason Leigh, Chris Penn, Lily Tomlin, Tim Robbins, Tom Waits, Frances McDormand, Lyle Lovett, etc &amp;#8230; There is also a jazz band the has some of my personal favorite musicians; Bobby Previte, Greg Cohen, and Bruce Fowler. The fact that the movie was based on the writings of Raymond Carver makes it all the more important to me. Carver&amp;#8217;s writings never seemed to lend themselves to film, but the screenplay managed to pull out the dialogue and make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movie &amp;#8216;Nashville&amp;#8217; featured 24 (!) main characters. The editing necessary to create a cohesive story was just amazing. It&amp;#8217;s a tough movie to watch and I end up fast-forwarding through a large number of the musical numbers, but it&amp;#8217;s still an important movie to me. It managed to capture at time period rather well. At some subliminal level it reminds me of my youth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are definite holes in my movie collection when it comes to Mr. Altman such as &amp;#8216;McCabe and Mrs. Miller&amp;#8217;, and &amp;#8216;The Player&amp;#8217;, and not all of his movies are classics (Ex. Dr T and His Women). But for me he still wins massive props for being an 81 year old director still willing to take the chances that he does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a nice bit of trivia while watching the special features from the MASH DVD (I&amp;#8217;m one of those nutty folks who actually watches the majority of the bonus features on DVDs). The use of announcements was used to give a cohesive element to the disparate vignettes. One of the shots of the speakers was shot at night with the moon in the background. Apparently at the time of the shooting, there was a moon landing happening at the same time. It&amp;#8217;s one of those ridiculous facts that will stick in my head whenever I see the film.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Donald Fagen</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/03/14/Donald-Fagen"/>
   <updated>2006-03-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/03/14/Donald-Fagen</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new Donald Fagen project &amp;#8216;Morph the Cat&amp;#8217; came out today and now I&amp;#8217;m happily grooving to Mr. Fagen&amp;#8217;s music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two events that finally got me into the music of Steely Dan and Messrs. Fagen and Becker. I was driving back to college during a time when I nothing more to listen to than FM radio. I feel completely spoiled today with a CD player or iPod my vehicle, but I did have several lucky occurrences from scanning the radio dial. I was on a length of highway 28 and caught a morning show that was featuring the music of Steely Dan. I managed to catch about 30 minutes of the show and heard such tunes as &amp;#8216;Babylon Sisters&amp;#8217;, &amp;#8216;Hey Nineteen&amp;#8217;, and &amp;#8216;FM&amp;#8217;. After getting back to the lowly college apartment, I borrowed the roommate&amp;#8217;s Citizen Steely Dan boxed set and became a fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime over that winter break, I had a lot of time on my hands (I believe this was pre-computer days) and spent most of a week when not tending bar, doing nothing but laying on our $25 Goodwill couch and reading. I loaded up the CD player with all four discs from the boxed set and spent a good part of each day absorbing the jazz influenced melodies and impeccable studio chops of the band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I occasionally get locked into musical patterns when I&amp;#8217;m stuck on an artist and listen to nothing but their entire catalog for weeks on end. This happens with artists such as &amp;#8216;Wilco&amp;#8217; or &amp;#8216;John Coltrane&amp;#8217;, but at least once a year I load up the mp3 player with every bit of Steely Dan, Donald Fagen, and Walter Becker music that I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s too early to judge the newest project, but it sounds like vintage Fagen, so I think I&amp;#8217;ll be quite content.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Muncie</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/03/06/Muncie-in-the-paper"/>
   <updated>2006-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/03/06/Muncie-in-the-paper</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend, the Chicago Tribune had an article that mentioned the current economic status of Muncie, IN. I had spent a good deal of the 90s attending school there at Ball State. It is a odd mix of a college town and a blue-collar town, where the college kids try to avoid the locals, and the locals blame everything bad on the school. Last summer Nathan and I made a quick drive-thru, and took a look around where I had spent so many years. I felt like my memories had to be wrong, that things weren&amp;#8217;t this run-down and pitiful when I had attended school. It turns out I was probably correct, and things had gone down considerably since I had moved on. It reminded me of watching &amp;#8216;Roger and Me&amp;#8217;, Muncie was rapidly turning in to Flint, MI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muncie was actually a sizeable town in comparison to where I had grown up. Aside from a couple of trips to visit my friend Travis in Lafayette, I hadn&amp;#8217;t spent any real time in a town that had actual sidewalks. I spend at least a two years of my Munice life walking around late at night on those sidewalks trying to make sense of things. I had worked at a local restaurant for nearly four years so I had a decent amount of interaction with the locals, and they really didn&amp;#8217;t like the school or the types of folks that the school brought in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of it&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;normalicy&amp;#8217; for lack of a better word, Muncie was the subject of a sociological study in the late 1920&amp;#8217;s, due to how &amp;#8216;average&amp;#8217; the population was. Being the home of Ball canning jars has not helped it keep up with the economic times, and the closing of the Delco plant, as well as a transmission plant that did work for GM have pretty much closed the doors on the town. These factory jobs that paid $25/hr are being replaced with Wal-Mart jobs that pay $9/hr. It was reported that the number of public school students on the free lunch program is now around 51%, with that number expected to grow fairly rapidly with one in four people living in poverty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a point in my when I nearly ended up a permanent resident. Everything I had seemingly wanted was there; an available music studio where I could work for 80 hrs/week, a coffee shop, a decent library, and some small degree of culture with free concerts at the school. Luckily, I made some decisions that I had doubted at the time, but have all turned out for the best. I had an opportunity to do my PhD there, but at that point I had decided that I really needed to go somewhere else for school. It&amp;#8217;s quite likely that I had the blinders of youth on when I lived there. It didn&amp;#8217;t matter that I was getting by on $430/mo and staying in a crappy apartment with no air-conditioning, and barely workable heating. I was doing what I wanted to do, and the environment was inconsequential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s sad to see something from my youth fall apart. It makes me doubt the very memories that make up that time period. This was the time where I think I discovered who I really was, and what I was capable of doing. I&amp;#8217;m not sure I would have ever came as far as I have without getting out of my hometown and growing up on my own.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Bad Plus</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/02/11/the-bad-plus"/>
   <updated>2006-02-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/02/11/the-bad-plus</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We caught &amp;#8216;The Bad Plus&amp;#8217; last night at one of my favorite venues, The Old Town School of Folk Music. Holy crap was that amazing. I&amp;#8217;ve been listening to their tunes for the past year or so, and even though their CDs were produced by Tchad Blake, the don&amp;#8217;t come anywhere close to demonstrating what the are capable of in a live setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The played a very tight set, highlighting their most recent project, &amp;#8216;Suspicious Activity&amp;#8217;. Each of the musicians were excellent of their respective instruments, but I&amp;#8217;d like to say something about the drummer, David King.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s rare to witness true excellence. To see someone so in command of their abilities that they have complete confidence in what they are doing. Something I enjoy in things like jazz music or college basket is the moments when someone steps up and discovers something amazing in their abilities. For that brief moment, they have found how excellent they can be. It&amp;#8217;s usually brief, and is most certainly something worth living for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When &amp;#8216;The Bad Plus&amp;#8217; began to play, and most particularly when David King began to play, it was pure excellence. He seemed so completely confident in his musical ideas and pursued them completely. It was fantastic and amazing, their set flew by and I wished that I could have seen the second performance that evening. They came out for a brief encore with their version of &amp;#8216;Flim&amp;#8217; by Aphex Twin. That in particular was a great little quota for me. That particular Aphex Twin project (Come to Daddy) was a huge influence on my when I was still in music school. To see someone performing the intricate electronic percussion parts live, was just superb.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Life as a Clock</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/02/09/life-as-a-clock"/>
   <updated>2006-02-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/02/09/life-as-a-clock</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Considering the 4.5 billion years of the planet compressed into one earth day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4:00 am - life begins (single cell organisms)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;// nothing advances for the next 16 hours&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;8:30 pm - first sea plants emerge&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;8:50 pm - first jellyfish and Ediacaran fauna&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;9:04 pm - trilobites appear&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;10:00 pm - first land plants&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;10:05 pm - first land creatures&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;10:24 pm - carboniferous forests emerge and first winged insects&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;11:00 pm - dinosaurs&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;11:38 pm - age of mammals&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;11:58:47 - humans emerge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relatively speaking, humans have been on the planet for about 77 seconds of a 24 hr day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way of looking at it is to stretch ones arms to represent the entire history of the earth. The distance from the fingertips of one hand to the wrist of the other represents the Precambrian (pre-fossil) era. All the complex life of the earth is represented by one hand, and the entire human history is represented by a single stroke of a medium-grained nail file.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>More - Short History of Nearly Everything</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/02/08/more%3A-a-short-history"/>
   <updated>2006-02-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/02/08/more:-a-short-history</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Deprived of water, the human body decays rapidly; within days the lips vanish (as if amputated), the gums blacken, the nose withers to half its length, and the skin contracts around the eyes to the degree that it becomes impossible to blink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The water we drink has been around since the earth was young. By 3.8 billion years ago the oceans had basically achieved their current volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water is incredibly fluid (pun), the molecular bond is strong enough to flow uphill when siphoned and cause pain from a belly flop , but weak enough to separate when diving into a pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve found something amazing on nearly every page of this book. I may have to grab the audio book to listen to in the car. There&amp;#8217;s so much information I can&amp;#8217;t absorb it all at once.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Short History of Nearly Everything</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2006/02/07/a-short-history-of-nearly-everything"/>
   <updated>2006-02-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2006/02/07/a-short-history-of-nearly-everything</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always had a fascination with science. If I remember back to my Kindergarden years my plan at the time was to become a chemist. I think it was just the cool instruments and lots of dangerous chemicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m about half-way through Bill Bryson&amp;#8217;s book A Short History of Nearly Everything and it&amp;#8217;s just amazing. I&amp;#8217;m sure it&amp;#8217;s far too watered down for anyone truly studying the sciences, but the analogies make things a bit more understandable for my feeble brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ex. If an atom were expanded to the size of a cathedral, the nucleus would be only about the size of fly, but a fly many thousands of times heaver than the cathedral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the days of diving suits that were connected to surface by long hoses divers would sometimes experience &amp;#8216;the squeeze&amp;#8217;. When the surface pumps failed, the air would leave the suite with such violence that the diver would literally be sucked into the helmet and hosepipe. All that was left in the suit were &amp;#8216;bones and some rags of flesh&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s amazing to realize how everything is under a slow motion. The fact that glass is actually viscous and is slowly being pulled down by gravity. Very old glass found in ancient cathedrals is noticeably thicker at the bottom of the pane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I open the book I find my brain aching a bit trying to comprehend the hugeness and smallness of the world. It&amp;#8217;s a good pain, its good to stretch the brain muscle.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2005</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2005/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2005-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2005/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember thinking that I needed to start learning more of the business world, so I drifted a bit away from fiction. Not too many new discoveries, but writers like TC Boyle continued to put out solid books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2005&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radio On - Sarah Vowell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Take the Cannoli - Sarah Vowell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sock - Penn Jillette&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Partly Cloudy Patriot - Sarah Vowell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Searching for Bobby Fischer - Fred Waitzkin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How We Are Hungry - David Eggers&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hoot - Carl Hiaasen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Amazing Adventures of Kavalier and Clay - Michael Chabon&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Will You Please Be Quiet, Please - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Wasp Factory - Iain Banks&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Coen Brothers - Ronald Borgan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Mischievous Art of Jim Flora - Irwin Chusid&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;After the Plague - T.C. Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas - Hunter S. Thompson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Tipping Point - Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Everything is Illuminated - Jonathan Safran Foer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Blink - Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Transmission - Hari Kunzru&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Never a City So Real: A Walk in Chicago - Alex Katlowitz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Weirdos in the Workplace - John Putzier&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Purple Cow - Seth Godin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Wall Street Meat - Andy Kessler&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Running Money - Andy Kessler&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bird by Bird - Anne Lamott&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Free Prize Inside - Seth Godin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;New High Intensity Training - Ellington Darden&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Never Eat Alone - Frank Farrazzi&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Automatic Millionaire - David Bach&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Assassination Vacation - Sarah Vowell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Freakonomics - Levitt &amp;#38; Dubner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;First, Break All the Rules - Buckingham and Coffman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;White Noise - Don DeLillo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Season on the Mat - Nolan Zavoral&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Lonesome Dove - Larry McMurtry&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince - J. K. Rowling&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All of Us - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Why Do Me Have Nipples - Mark Leyner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;My Friend Leonard - James Frey&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Love Supreme - Ashley Kahn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Chasin&amp;#8217; the Train - J. C. Thomas&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Aloft - Chang-Rae Lee&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ascension - Eric Nisenson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Blood Meridian - Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No Country for Old Men - Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Golden Compass - Philip Pullman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Conference Misery Pt. 2</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2005/10/21/conference-misery-pt2"/>
   <updated>2005-10-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2005/10/21/conference-misery-pt2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last session of the first day was on &amp;#8216;Protecting Your Software Investment&amp;#8217;. The description of the session follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Patching, Security (Internal and External) , Speed of Access, Disaster Preparedness, Data Recovery, Backup Options&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a sucker for anything related to disaster recovery and security, so no matter how badly I really wanted to leave so I could go home and pass out in a Nyquil induced haze, I forced myself to attend. I was graciously rewarded with fountains of knowledge. While there was 75 minutes set aside for the presentation, it was drawn out to a painful 24 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Play-by-play:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;patching: only apply if necessary, so, uh, if not necessary, don&amp;#8217;t apply&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;security: use some antivirus product&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;speed of access: if things are slow, upgrade to gigabit&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;disaster preparedness: have a disaster recovery plan (described as, &amp;#8220;a list of things to do to recover in case of disaster&amp;#8221;)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;data recovery: make backups&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;backup options: not discussed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no discussion of how to patch, how to determine what constitutes a necessary patch, example DR plans, backup rotations, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, I need to let it go. It was only two days of my life gone to pot.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Conference Misery</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2005/10/20/conference-misery"/>
   <updated>2005-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2005/10/20/conference-misery</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;ve survived another mind-numbing conference. Powerpoint is certainly the work of the devil, if for no other reason that it is very successful in making learning tedious. Session after session of green text on white templates, with monotonous speakers droning on about topics they care nothing about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I actually picked up two useful bits of knowledge that could have taken the sum total of 25 seconds, rather than two days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favorite buzzwords/cliches (from a single 45 minute lecture):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spark creativity&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;create a bridge&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;improve communications&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;extending the power&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;building a bridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most annoying tic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many of you here are using version X?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How many of you here are using version X.X?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How many of you here are using software X and software Y?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How many of you here enjoyed breakfast?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last session I attended, this type of question was posed 34 times before I quit counting. The constant question asking/hand raising and NOBODY CARES about the responses. None of the content material is modified in regards to the audience responses. It&amp;#8217;s like grade school all over again.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Resumes and Such</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2005/08/02/resumes-and-stuff"/>
   <updated>2005-08-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2005/08/02/resumes-and-stuff</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;#8217;ll start taking notes here about resume&amp;#8217;s and applying for work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve spend the last week digging through 85+ resumes trying to find competent individuals. This is no fun, and applicants seem to have the express goal of trying to make it harder for me. This makes me mad and makes me not want to hire a single person. I&amp;#8217;ve checked into helper monkeys, but they&amp;#8217;re to smart to take a sysadmin gig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;on your resume, have a working phone number and/or email address. When I call a number and get a &amp;#8216;no longer in service message&amp;#8217;, I have to throw the paper object in my hand away. I can&amp;#8217;t even be troubled to crumble it with anger, it&amp;#8217;s just not worth it. I am easy, I will even go the extra mile to type out an email to an applicants address, if they have one. Having neither of these makes Hulk mad for wasting his time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;answering machine message. &amp;#8220;This is &lt;em&gt;cough, cough&lt;/em&gt; Ted (long pause) I&amp;#8217;m, we&amp;#8217;re not here right now, leave a message &lt;em&gt;wheeze&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221; aka, I am so high right now, I can&amp;#8217;t even record a greeting on my phone. Please put me in charge of very expensive equipment, and millions of dollars in user-data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;resume length. Unless you&amp;#8217;ve done something really, really kick-ass (like discovered cold-fusion, the real cold-fusion, not the crappy macromedia product), don&amp;#8217;t send 7 page resumes in 15pt font (ok, never-ever do this, even if you did discover cold-fusion). Although I do appreciate the consideration of the aged and sight impaired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;word choice. The objective contains the following words: seize, opportunity, lead, grow, advance, terrific. This person is in all likelihood, lying. If they are truly this positive, I would hate them anyway, and never hire them. But I may interview them just out of pure malice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPA. If your GPA is 2.0 (on a four point scale) don&amp;#8217;t bring that to my attention. Sure, there&amp;#8217;s grade inflation in college, but 2.0 = C = Average = I don&amp;#8217;t want to talk to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spelling. &amp;#8216;PERLFERLS&amp;#8217; : I can guess at least two things this may be, but I shouldn&amp;#8217;t have to. F7 is spellcheck in most applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical Skills. Don&amp;#8217;t list every single bloody version of every piece of software. That&amp;#8217;s really fantastic that you&amp;#8217;ve used IE 5.0/5.5/6.0/6.1 or RedHat 7.0/7.2/8.0/8.8/9.0, but I don&amp;#8217;t care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>remix - rewind - regurgitate</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2005/06/29/remix-rewind-regurgitate"/>
   <updated>2005-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2005/06/29/remix-rewind-regurgitate</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The current issue of wired magazine arrived the other day (I thought my subscription ran out 5 months ago) with the cover saying something about &amp;#8216;Remix Now!&amp;#8217;. I&amp;#8217;ve been hearing how &amp;#8216;remixing&amp;#8217; is the new buzzword, which makes me quite nauseous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not certain who started this, but it&amp;#8217;s an unfortunate terminology. I think of remixing in the audio world, where singles were remixed to increase their playing time for the dance environment. This eventually evolved into increasingly disparate remixes moving further and further away from the original track in question. The mixes would bring in influences from a variety of musics and cultures (Ex. Bill Laswell, Aphex Twin, and dozens of others). But this &amp;#8216;remixing&amp;#8217; has been around forever; composers often quoted/borrowed/modified from other composes, writers quoted/borrowed/modified the works of other writers. This is nothing new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vladamir Ussachevsky&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Wireless Fantasy combined a sample of Wagner&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Parsifal&amp;#8217; with a sample of the first transatlantic radio transmission by Marconi. An entire school of electronic music was devoted to this sort of &amp;#8216;ReMixing&amp;#8217;. Music Concrete, developed by Pierre Schaeffer and Pierre Henri used tape and phonographs to create new forms of music. Burroughs sampled text and reorganized it, college freshmen photoshopped their roomates faces on porn photos. It&amp;#8217;s all been done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick in the modern age seems to be repackaging something that&amp;#8217;s been around forever and call it something new (is this branding?). You see this often in the world of &amp;#8216;Business Books&amp;#8217; where common sense is repackaged and resold as a &amp;#8216;Brand New Business Methodology that will Transform Visionary Infomediaries and Administrate Market Driven Paradigms that Adhere to the Highest Standards of Quality&amp;#8217;, which usually just translates into treating your customers well and not being an ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument could be made that the newness of this relates to the availability of tools to aid in this repackaging, but what is easier than and pen &amp;amp; paper? Digital tools can make this easier, but sometimes too easy. How many of the so-called &amp;#8216;mash-ups&amp;#8217; can be listened to more than once (if even once). It&amp;#8217;s just more easy-bake culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This repackaging bothers me since it shows such and obvious disregard for history and culture. This has always been here, it&amp;#8217;s a part of humanity, it&amp;#8217;s how we evolve ideas. There is no &amp;#8216;Intelligent Design&amp;#8217; in creativity, it&amp;#8217;s more like the hobnobbing of differences that transform into new concepts.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Southern change gonna come at last</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2005/06/28/southern-change-gonna-come-at-last"/>
   <updated>2005-06-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2005/06/28/southern-change-gonna-come-at-last</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a face I&amp;#8217;d seen a thousand times at every Derby I&amp;#8217;d ever been to. I saw it, in my head, as the mask of the whiskey gentry&amp;#8211;a pretentious mix of booze, failed dreams and a terminal identity crisis; the inevitable result of too much inbreeding in a closed and ignorant culture. - HST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trip went well, aside from a one hour delay b/w boarding and take-off, but we had no connecting flights, so the stress was minimal. We arrived and in short order consumed great amounts of BBQ and deep-fried corn on the cob. The south is always the bastion of healthy consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A trip to the half-price book store pretty much capped off the night. I actually located two books on my streamlined list. With the lack of book storage, I&amp;#8217;ve severely reduced my book purchasing. The local library is decent, and I&amp;#8217;ve found myself being much more critical about what I&amp;#8217;ll read/buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I mention it was deadly hot and humid? After living in the midwest for the majority of my life, and surviving in Florida for two years, I can handle pretty much any weather. Hot and humid weather just sucks. For me I&amp;#8217;ve learned that minimal food and massive amounts of water are the only way to survive the heat without one&amp;#8217;s mood turning beastly foul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day was spent browsing the local hipster area along Bardstown Rd. for books and music. Ear-Extacy is a mighty fine music store. The staff actually seem knowledgeable, which is a grand treat from the land of Borders/Best Buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening we hit the Louisville Bats game. I usually enjoy minor-league baseball games. The stadiums are decent and the cost is reasonable. The problem with any public event in the south, is the unbelievable number of young child bearing couples. From what I gather, unmarried by 21 is rare indeed. The crowd of screaming, crying, rapidily sunburning children made the game nearly unbearable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished off the evening with a drive around some of the rich areas of Louisville. There is a lot of old money in this town, and tremendous amounts of beautiful brick homes. A couple of episodes of Northern Exposure later, and I was ready to crash. Northern Exposure always seems like my idea of heaven; people discussing actual topics (movies, books, philosophy) rather than reality TV. That&amp;#8217;s why its called fiction, because it doesn&amp;#8217;t really exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday was pretty slow, a trip to a local brunch for a great deal of food consumption, a bit of hanging around and the back to the airport. Pretty nice weekend to get away. It doesn&amp;#8217;t look like we&amp;#8217;ll get a real vacation in this year, so we&amp;#8217;re trying to make the most of a couple of short trips.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wilco May 5, 2007</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2005/05/09/wilco-050705"/>
   <updated>2005-05-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2005/05/09/wilco-050705</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Got to see Wilco again this weekend. The last night of a four night run at the Vic Theatre. All for nights were being taped for a DVD due out this fall. Pretty amazing set list, but the technical issues hurt the momentum a bit. Yep, that is indeed 35 songs. The band looked wiped out when the show ended (8:15 to 11:59).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set List&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misunderstood (w/ Horns)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Company in My Back&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Late Greats&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hummingbird&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;At Least That&amp;#8217;s What You Said&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;IATTBYH&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Shot in the Arm&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Muzzle of Bees&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Via Chicago&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Handshake Drugs&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Jesus, etc.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Say You Miss Me&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Theologians&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;m the Man Who Loves You (w/ Horns)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;(Break: equipment issues)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;m The Man Who Loves You (take two)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Poor Places&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Wishful Thinking&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Spiders (Kidsmoke)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sunken Treasure&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;(Break: equipment issues)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Political Science&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Be Not So Fearful&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Passenger Side&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Heavy Metal Drummer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Comment&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Lonely 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;New Madrid&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I Shall Be Released&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Someday Soon&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Far, Far Away&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;California Stars (w/ Horns)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Magazine Called Sunset&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Promising&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Candyfloss&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;She&amp;#8217;s A Jar&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hoodoo Voodoo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Something in the Air&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2004</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2004-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the old job and moved up near Chicago. I was an IT department of one, trying to upgrade and entire office by myself. I&amp;#8217;m surprised that I had enough time to read the books that I did. I didn&amp;#8217;t run across many new authors this year, but did manage to read more Richard Yates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2004&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire - J. K. Rowling&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix - J. K. Rowling&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Syrup - Maxx Barry&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Puttermesser Papers - Cynthia Ozick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Kingdom of Fear - Hunter S. Thompson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Summer Rain - Jon Konrath&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Eats, Shoots, and Leaves - Lynne Truss&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How to Talk Dirty and Influence People - Lenny Bruce&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Wilco: Learning How to Die - Greg Kot&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hacker Cracker - Ejoui Nuwhere&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Stranger Than Fiction - Chuck Palahnuick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Learned Pigs and Fireproof Women - Ricky Jay&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Great Gatsby - F. Scott Fitzgerald&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How to Own a Continent - Ryan Russell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Acts of the Apostles - John F. X. Sundman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Across the Nightingale Floor - Lian Hearn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Crypto - Stephen Levy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Teeth - Hugh Gallagher&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Skinny Dip - Carl Hiaasen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Grass for his Pillow - Lian Hearn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Brilliance of the Moon - Lian Hearn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Zero-Day Exploit - Rob Shein&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Collected Short Stories - Richard Yates&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Getting Things Done - David Allen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Oblivion: Stories - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If the River Was Whiskey - T. C. Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Good School - Richard Yates&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Inner Circle - T. C. Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Game of Thrones - George R. R. Martin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Going Corporate - Brad Embree&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;MASH - Richard Hooker&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tom Waits: Wild Years - Jay S. Jacobs&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Budding Prospects - T. C. Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Wilco Book - Wilco&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mind Wide Open - Stephen Johnson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Rain Fall - Barry Eisler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Alaska</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/12/09/alaska"/>
   <updated>2004-12-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/12/09/alaska</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been checking out this journal for awhile, &amp;#8220;To Philly, From Alaska, w/ love&amp;#8221;. This guy seems to be living out my &amp;#8216;Northern Exposure&amp;#8217;-inspired dreams of running away to Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;In Alaska, the bigger rivers that connect villages become state highways when they freeze.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds like perfection.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LAGQ</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/11/22/lagq"/>
   <updated>2004-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/11/22/lagq</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While browsing the local Sunday paper, I happend to see that the Los Angeles Guitar Quartet was performing in town that evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concert was at the University of Chicago campus, w/ the poor directions we were given, we enjoyed a nice tour of the south-side of Chicago. There are a few rough areas down there. When we hit Comiskey Park, we don&amp;#8217;t even hit the local restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple of detours, we managed to find street parking and grabbed a couple of available tix. Even feeling a bit old and out of place in the college environment, there were enough old folks so we didn&amp;#8217;t stand out too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They LAGQ played two nice sets, and were pretty tight for the most part. Some nice originals, and appropriate arrangements (aside from the Stravinsky, which doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to translate well to the guitar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LAGQ is similar to the Kronos Quartet in the sense of being a bit more adventurous in their vocabulary then the standard ensembles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to check out more music. There&amp;#8217;s always so much going on in this town, I need to make it more of a priority.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>From Neil Steinberg</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/11/19/from-neil-steinberg"/>
   <updated>2004-11-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/11/19/from-neil-steinberg</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our office shares a lobby with the Illinois Institute of Art. Its students are always scattered around at small tables, meticulously going at a pad of onion paper with a straight edge and a drafting instrument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sometimes pause and take advantage of their being so focused to really look at them: all of 19 or 20, thin as pencils, dressed in the latest silly fashion and pouring their souls into a rendering of a costume or a house or a frog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;If only,&amp;#8221; I say silently to their future self, 20 years down the line, trapped in some accounting office or insurance firm, &amp;#8220;you could see how you look at this moment. It would break your heart.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>book fair</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/06/05/book-fair"/>
   <updated>2004-06-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/06/05/book-fair</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While Jen spent the day hiking 26 miles through the streets of Chicago doing the Avon Walk for Cancer, I spent the day with my brother at the Chicago Printer&amp;#8217;s Row Book Fair. Five blocks of booksellers, food, and live readings. It was amazing to see the streets packed with folks with that much interest in reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to see Chuck Palahniuk perform &amp;#8216;Guts&amp;#8217;. Only three people fainted during the reading, bringing the total on his reading tour up to 43 people who have passed out during the performance. The paramedics came and took them away. It was quite a visceral experience. Chuck was giving out coupons to folks who asked questions during the Q&amp;amp;A session to receive gifts from him in the mail He really seems to make an honest attempt to connect to his readers rather than just pimping his books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking around a bit, we tried to catch David Eggers. I&amp;#8217;ve been a fan of his writing for the last few years. His McSweeney&amp;#8217;s publications has brought attention to quite a number of interesting authors. The place was packed and bursting with heat. We ended up bailing and walked around a bit. I managed to add another book to my Richard Yates collection (A Good School) and nearly completed my T. Coraghessan Boyle collection (If the River Was Whiskey and Budding Prospects) for $5 each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also managed to meet briefly with John McNally, but didn&amp;#8217;t stick around for the panel. It had been a long day of books and far too much food. The day of food savagery concluded with Gino&amp;#8217;s East and a White Sox game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jen successfully completely the first round of the walk, all the way from Soldier&amp;#8217;s Field to a park near our apartment. She was a bit shaky, but sounded better after I left. Tomorrow is another 14 miles, and after that, lots of sleep. It was pretty impressive to be around all these folks who contributed so much time and effort to a cause. I believe they raised something like 6 million dollars for breast cancer research and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite a wonderful day. It&amp;#8217;s fantastic to be living so close to the city, so many opportunities that I&amp;#8217;ve been looking forward to enjoying. I still get excited just seeing that amazing skyline coming into view through the windshield.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Peaceful Night</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/05/21/peaceful-night"/>
   <updated>2004-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/05/21/peaceful-night</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a good, peaceful evening. White Sox game on low (beating Minnesota), a few windows open, and nice steady rainfall in the background. Jen is out for the evening, so I&amp;#8217;m catching up on some mundane IT tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is good, this is calming, the quiet is very much enjoyed. For further excitement, I expect a fair amount of reading will round out the evening following the games conclusion. Yep, this is the pure, burning excitement of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just had a strange flashback to Florida, coming out the library on a summer evening. Usually hanging out with John. Strange to think, I&amp;#8217;d just be leaving that state about now, if it hadn&amp;#8217;t been for a ridiculously cancerous professor. Knowing I&amp;#8217;ll never have to see that bastard again for the rest of my life makes this evening all that much better. I do miss the few friends I made down there, but learning how they&amp;#8217;re kicking ass (one of them also ridding themselves of the same bastard professor) is good enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that the only hope you have when dealing with such petty individuals as this professor is to simply remove oneself from the situation, and proceed to be more successful than they are. I don&amp;#8217;t particularly measure success with money, but I know that this individual does, and knowing that I&amp;#8217;m better paid then he is can be mildly amusing (but then again, I do have a work a full week, not the 3-day schedule that he whines about, but I don&amp;#8217;t find myself running sound for dance performances, trying to scrape up some extra cash). This professor is a very petty and pathetic man, and recent insight has added unfortunate knowledge to just how pathetic he is. But I no longer have to deal with it, and he has to live with it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fog of War</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/05/13/fog-of-war"/>
   <updated>2004-05-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/05/13/fog-of-war</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just finished watched the latest Errol Morris film, Fog of War. Morris&amp;#8217; films are always compelling, he has a definite knack for discovering worthy subjects. This time the subject was Robert McNamara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do hope that at the age of 85, I have some semblance of coherence and memory that Mr. McNamara retains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;At my age, 85, I&amp;#8217;m at an age where I can look back and derive some conclusions about my actions. My rule has been to try to learn, try to understand what happened. Develop the lessons and pass them on.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the film, MacNamara discusses his viewpoint and roles in some of the greatest events in American History; WWI, The Cold War, The Cuban Missile Crisis, The Vietnam War, and the past and future implications of Nuclear Weapons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film is organized around eleven lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empathize with your enemy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Rationality will not save us&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;There&amp;#8217;s something beyond one&amp;#8217;s self&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Maximize efficiency&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Proportionality should be a guideline in war&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Get the data&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Belief and Seeing are both often wrong&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Be prepared to reexamine your reasoning&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In order to do good, you may have to engage in evil&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Never say never&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You can&amp;#8217;t change human nature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was pretty amazing how he coldly he could discuss the ending of thousands of lives in war and yet tear up when discussing the assassination of President Kennedy. I imagine one has to be able to distance oneself from the realties of human loss through statistics and rationalizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The primary role of the President of the United States is to keep the nation out of war&amp;#8221; - J.F. Kennedy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Selby</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/04/28/selby"/>
   <updated>2004-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/04/28/selby</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Scream Looking for a Mouth:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite authors, Hubert Selby Jr. passed away. He was the author of &amp;#8220;Last Exit to Brooklyn&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;Requiem for a Dream&amp;#8221; and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His books were huge for me when I was in college. &amp;#8220;The Demon&amp;#8221; was just pure hell ripping through the pages. One of the most honest looks at stupid male behavior, it always served as a great reminder to me of how capable everyone is of self-destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got into Selby from Rollins, and have a few books with Selby&amp;#8217;s signature. His most recent writings didn&amp;#8217;t capture the full-on fury of his early works, but if I remember correctly, &amp;#8216;Last Exit to Brooklyn&amp;#8221; took something like 6 years to write, working every night. The section featuring Tralala, took 2.5 years just to properly develop the character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selby left school at 15 and joined the merchant marines. He contrated tuberclulosis and lost one of his lungs. He went through alcohol and heroin addiction. He body was so ravaged, Lou Reed described him as looking like a crouched letter &amp;#8216;S&amp;#8217;. He was one of the most intense writers I&amp;#8217;ve ever come across, no one writes like &amp;#8216;Cubby&amp;#8217;, I&amp;#8217;ll be re-reading some of his books soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>spoiled</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/04/16/spoiled"/>
   <updated>2004-04-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/04/16/spoiled</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I could easily get spoiled by days like today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;76 degrees and gorgeous. I swiped Jen&amp;#8217;s iPod and loaded in with some new music I got last night (Grant Lee Phillips and My Morning Jacket) and headed out to walk along the lake front. It&amp;#8217;s so great to have access to Lake Michigan only 10 minutes away. There&amp;#8217;s no way I&amp;#8217;d want to move to the western suburbs and lose that. It was nice to see folks outside, enjoying the weather. It was mostly yuppie housewives and old folks, but there were a few artists here and there sketching the water and the million dollar homes that exist along the lake in Evanston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was good to be away from computers for awhile and just remember how much I enjoy music. I&amp;#8217;ve actually been playing a bit more as well, getting the classical guitar chops in shape (slow, painfully slow).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to get a bit of work done before Jen gets home. I believe deep-dish pizza is in order for this evening.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>long weekend</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/04/15/long-weekend"/>
   <updated>2004-04-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/04/15/long-weekend</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Taking the day off tomorrow, been working about 11 days straight after last weekend&amp;#8217;s domain move fiasco. The weather&amp;#8217;s been pretty amazing, springlike (mid 70s) and quite comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Took off an hour early after fighting with the president&amp;#8217;s workstation. It was fantastic to drive home with the windows down and the new Wilco CD (A Ghost is Born) at full volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from work, the rest of life is starting to settle into place. It&amp;#8217;s nice to have the health club membership for stress release and high-speed internet for getting work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jen and I are heading east to visit the folks this weekend. I have a few things left to drag back to the new homestead. Hopefully tomorrow will be productive, I haven&amp;#8217;t had a full day to myself in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>shrink</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/03/29/shrink"/>
   <updated>2004-03-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/03/29/shrink</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Up later that I should be, can&amp;#8217;t seem to sleep much lately. It&amp;#8217;s been a few days since I&amp;#8217;ve gotten more than six hours. That used to be no biggie, and I was cranking on the coffee, but I&amp;#8217;m down to at most a single can of diet coke a day for caffeine intake. This is just brain-not-shutting up energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking a lot about the future, the next step, the next plans, plenty to do, just need the time to do it. We actually made the plunge and got cable tv, along with the high-speed access. I&amp;#8217;m hating myself for all the time wasted. I couldn&amp;#8217;t even enjoy the sopranos (that and the shield are the only reason I even wanted cable), my brain just kept chugging along in the background, digging in little reminders of time wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still haven&amp;#8217;t found a decent health club in the area. There are plenty of big-ass Bally&amp;#8217;s, but I&amp;#8217;d rather have a smaller, independent place. I can feel my muscles shriveling from a lack of activity for the past month. I was benching and squatting more than ever in my life, and it&amp;#8217;s going to take more catch up time just to get back what I already lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been reading about a few small, independent computer companies and really think that&amp;#8217;s the way I need to go. Especially after meeting a few of the consultants that are out there, I think I could really make it happen. I&amp;#8217;m not worried about the technical side, but I go have quite a few (personal) networking skills to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time, time, time &amp;#8230; it all comes down to time, and never having enough of it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>packing</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2004/02/28/packing"/>
   <updated>2004-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2004/02/28/packing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spent the day clearning out the room, and dumping everything into the basement. Tomorrow, the plan is to dig through the 13+ boxes of books, and hopefully find a few that can be disposed of. I&amp;#8217;m very particular w/ getting rid of books, they&amp;#8217;re tied to too many memories of where I was when I heard of a particular author, or when I read a particular book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I finally found Bukowski and Selby in the Ball State libary. Books were much harder to locate back then, there was no Borders, Barns &amp;amp; Noble, or amazon. I had to make the hour plus drive to Lafayette just to find something by Hunter S. Thompson or Mark Leyner. I haven&amp;#8217;t had all my books in a singular location in over a decade, and I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to filling a few bookshelves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still ripping music, filling up the 120 gig HDD on the file server. The amount of books and music I own is pretty staggering for someone who holds onto nothing of sentimental value. I relate to the world via music and text, it&amp;#8217;s all I got going for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to just digging into the new job and getting started, the feeling of waiting and anticipation drags me down and distracts me from current projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spent a good deal of today thinking and planning. One thousand years from now, my life could be reconstructed from the endless To-Do lists that are constantly re-organized, re-edited, and re-prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to get a couple more hours of work before passing out. I&amp;#8217;ve had a stack of DVDs that I need to get to some day. I havent&amp;#8217;t sat down and watched a movie in quite a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2003</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2003/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2003-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2003/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2003 was the year I finally got back into Literature. There were even several short trips to Indianapolis to load up on used books. The end of my work days were usually spent at a bookstore, either studying or reading. I remember being in school and thinking just how happy I would be to make enough money to afford coffee and a book whenever I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2003&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;American Scream: The Bill Hicks Story - Cynthia True&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Pattern Recognition - William Gibson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Empire Falls - Richard Russo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Triggerfish Twist - Tim Dorsey&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bum Town - Tony Fitzpatrick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dirty Blvd - Tony Fitzpatrick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All Tomorrow&amp;#8217;s Parties - William Gibson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Friend of the Earth - T.C. Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Double Whammy - Carl Hiassen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sick Puppy - Carl Hiassen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Basket Case - Carl Hiassen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Stupid White Men - Michael Moore&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Real Conversations Vol. 1 - V. Vale&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Survivor - Chuck Palahnuick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Culture Jam - Kalle Lasn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reefer Maddness - Eric Schlosser&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Masters of Doom - David Kushner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Million Little Pieces - James Frey&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Team Rodent - Carl Hiassen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Trainspotting - Irvine Welsch&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Close to the Machine - Ellen Ullman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a Slippery Slope - Spalding Gray&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Morning, Noon, and Night - Spalding Gray&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nobody&amp;#8217;s Fool - Richard Russo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Rivethead - Ben Hamper&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Devil in the White City - Erik Larson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Stormy Weather - Carl Hiassen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Drop City - T.C. Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fugitives and Refugees - Chuck Palahnuick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Running with Scissors - Augusten Burrroughs&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Stiff: The Curious Life of Human Cadavers - Mary Roach&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tourist Season - Carl Hiassen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Dark Elf Trilogy - R.A. Salvatore&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Soulforge - Margaret Weis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Lies, and the Lying Liars - Al Franken&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dude, Where&amp;#8217;s My Country - Michael Moore&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The 158 lb Marriage - John Irving&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Death&amp;#8217;s Acre - Bill Bass and Jon Jefferson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Return of the King - J.R.R. Tolkein&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Corrections - Jonathan Franzen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Broken Summers - Henry Rollins&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Easter Parade - Richard Yates&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Harry Potter and the Sorcer&amp;#8217;s Stone - J.K. Rowling&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets - J.K. Rowling&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban - J.K. Rowling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Little Reminder</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2003/11/29/a-little-reminder"/>
   <updated>2003-11-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2003/11/29/a-little-reminder</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until one is committed, there is hesitancy. the chance to draw back, always ineffectiveness concerning all acts of initiative (and creation). There is one elemental truth, the ignorance of which kills countless ideas and splendid plans - - - that the moment one definitely commits oneself, then Providence moves all. All sorts of things occur to help one that would never otherwise have occurred. A whole stream of events issue from the decision, raising in one&amp;#8217;s favor all manner of incidents and meetings and material assistance which no one could have dreamed would come his or her way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you can do or dream, you can begin it. Boldness has genius, power and magic in it. Begin it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;Goethe&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Michael Moore</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2003/10/15/Michael-Moore"/>
   <updated>2003-10-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2003/10/15/Michael-Moore</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Headed into the city last night to catch Michael Moore at Northwestern. Pretty cool way to spend the evening. We hit Philly&amp;#8217;s Best for grinders then drove mindlessly around campus before locating the hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough, it actually increased my optimism rather than depressed me with the facts. The facts are slowly trickling out about the Bush regime, and the horrible atrocities that have been committed. I can&amp;#8217;t imagine being a parent, and having your child heading overseas for such loose and pathetic excuses. But seeing such an enourmous crowd gathered to hear him speak was pretty exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moore made the point that soldiers make a pact with the country. They are willing to die to defend our country, but that they trust the country not to put them unnecessarily in harms way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been digging Mr. Moore&amp;#8217;s work since &amp;#8220;Roger &amp;amp; Me&amp;#8221; (1989). I remember hanging out at my friend Travis&amp;#8217;s house and for the first time experiencing a movie that brought up all these issues that I knew were around, but I had no background to understand them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully next fall will be a turning point, that the voting public will actually remember the insideous activities of our puppet in command and make a more informed choice. At least there are a couple of relevant candidates out there that can make a stand this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to top it off, arriving at work and finding out that the cubs blew it in the 8th inning just really started off the day in a fine, fine way.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wilco</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2003/09/22/wilco"/>
   <updated>2003-09-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2003/09/22/wilco</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Saw Wilco friday night. Such an amazing show. It&amp;#8217;s been great finally seeing these bands I&amp;#8217;ve listen to for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set List:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;#8217;s the World Got In Store&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Kicking Television&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Shot In the Arm&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;m Always In Love&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Late Greats&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Magazine Called Sunset&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Box Full of Letters&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Kingpin&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;m the Man Who Loves You&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Poor Places&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reservations&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I Am Trying To Break Your Heart&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;War On War&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Misunderstood&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Pieholden Suite&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;California Stars Encore 1:&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Jesus, etc.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Handshake Drugs&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cars Can&amp;#8217;t Escape&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hoodoo Voodoo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encore 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christ For President&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Casino Queen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Passenger Side&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I Must Be High&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Outtamind (Outtasite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &amp;#8216;handshake drugs&amp;#8217; they brought out the drummer (who reminded me of Chris, formerly of 12 Rods) and guitarist of Carla Bozulich&amp;#8217;s Red Headed Stranger (opening act). Such an amazing musical moment.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reminder</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2003/08/20/reminder"/>
   <updated>2003-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2003/08/20/reminder</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had a good reminder the other day, a nice email that reminded me of a big decision made, and how so correct it was. I took a big chance, and it didn&amp;#8217;t really work out at the time, but things have fallen in place much better than I had ever thought they would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back on the past year of work I really managed to get a lot accomplished. I knocked out the Solaris Certifications and am a MCSE. I achieved most of my goals in regards to network security and feel much better about the state of the company security. There are few things left to do, but I think I&amp;#8217;ll be moving on before long. I&amp;#8217;m really looking forward about moving to Chicago. I used to keep a deskop background of the Chicago skyline as a reminder of how much I wanted to live in the city. The access to that much art and music really excites me. Hopefully things will fall into place before long, and I&amp;#8217;ll be on to the next stage of my life. I had a lot of support from my friends, and am very thankful for the opportunities I&amp;#8217;ve been given.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>vacation</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2003/08/01/vacation"/>
   <updated>2003-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2003/08/01/vacation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ugh, such a trauma to return from vacation, experiencing something new everyday, not knowing what the day will bring, and then returning to a structured existence. The body and soul take a bit of time to adjust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thursday (6/19) - leave from MDW to SEA (hurrah for direct flights), grab luggage and rental car (2003 chrysler sebring) and head northward to the town of Everett to stay at Kim &amp;amp; Mike&amp;#8217;s home for the evening&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;friday (6/20)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;breakfast w/ Kim and then northward towards Vancouver, B.C.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;it&amp;#8217;s good to see Kim and Mike again, glad he&amp;#8217;s finally back from the Middle East, they seem to be doing very well, very happy for them&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;nice drive through the rain and gorgeous countryside, bit of a tense border crossing (intense men asking what we did for a living, best advised not to joke w/ these folks)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;too early to check in, drive around trying to locate botanical gardens, instead opt for chinatown&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;very peaceful rain through most of the day, almost impossible to find public restrooms in vancouver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;spend and hour fighting w/ streets that change names, but manage to locate the hotel (Century Plaza Hotel and Spa)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;rest a bit, then have dinner in overpriced restaurant in hotel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;saturday (6/21)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hit the local town, find the beach and watch the ships for hours&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;spend time in Kitsilano walking, walking, walking&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;great food at the &amp;#8216;Restaurant from Hell&amp;#8217;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;try to make it to the vancouver canadians baseball time, but there&amp;#8217;s nowhere to park&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;check out the downtown area near the hotel, can&amp;#8217;t believe how clean this town is&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;dinner at a mediocrie thai restaurant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sunday (6/22)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;head to granville island in the AM, pretty rainy so the crowds are mild&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;the market on the island is fantastic, i really want to live somewhere w/ access to this much fresh food&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;meet an older couple from alberta (?), very polite folks, very canadian&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;head to stanley park (1000 acres), discover that the aquarium is $17 and spend the time walking around the park instead. Very pretty area, the folks here are so polite. I feel like just another rude american here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;monday (6/23)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;head south to seattle, find nathan &amp;amp; jodi&amp;#8217;s apt w/ some difficulty (again, raods changing names)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;head out for thai food, used cd stores, public market, monorail&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;dinner at &amp;#8216;chinook&amp;#8217;s&amp;#8217;, nice view of the boats on the water. I feel bad for any company when i&amp;#8217;m around the water, i can just stare for hours. Being on the water is the only place i really feel relaxed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tuesday (6/24)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;out for breakfast (amazing coffee)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;check out the zoo and a local beach. It would be so nice to be close enough to the beach to take one&amp;#8217;s lunch break there&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;dinner in freemont, hit some used bookstores and pick up the new Jay Farrar&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;meet up w/ Kim and catch the show at &amp;#8216;the empty space&amp;#8217;. it&amp;#8217;s good to see what nathan is up to&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;hang out with nathan after jen goes to sleep, get cds of &amp;#8216;Blake&amp;#8217;s Cinema&amp;#8217;, it&amp;#8217;s good to hear those tunes again. nathan is about the only person w/ a similar sense of humor, we can actually bounce ideas off one another and actually keep up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wed (6/25)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leave seattle, head east to Roslyn (where Northern Exposure was filmed)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;nice drive, very pretty countryside&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Roslyn was a great experience. I have such an emotional attachment to the characters and stories&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;lunch at &amp;#8216;the Brick&amp;#8217;, possibly the best french-fries of my life. It is indeed the coolest bar i&amp;#8217;ve ever been to in my life. The only bar i&amp;#8217;ve ever been where i truly wouldn&amp;#8217;t mind hanging out. The played the best collection of music i&amp;#8217;ve ever heard in a bar (uncle tupelo, phish, dar williams, allman brothers). It was a place that made me feel very content&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;sad to leave, but southward to portland&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;bit of a long drive, but beautiful countryside. I think the highest peak while driving was about 3000 ft. The little rental car was having some issues, but we made it ok&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;find the hotel in portland (the mark spencer), walk around near the hotel, find a fairly decent thai restaurant&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;head to powell&amp;#8217;s city of books &amp;#8230; an entire city block of books . . nirvanna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thurs (6/26)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;walk the entierty of the city of portland, nice lunch in the downtown plaza&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;again, watch the boats on the river&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;back to powell&amp;#8217;s at night, that store alone would be worth moving for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fri (6/27)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;head out to washington park for the japanese gardens and the rose gardens&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;the public transportation is great, no problems at all&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;back to the downtown area, more walking, walking, walking&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;out to dinner and a tour of the portland underground for a pretty interesting history of the shanghai trade&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;pack up for the home trip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sat (6/28)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pack up, and than northward to SEA&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;plane is an hour late in leaving &amp;#8230; stress . . the concert starts at 7:30, the flight is due to land at 6:20&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;flight lands around 7:00, after baggage and car location, we hit the road about 7:40&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;arrive about 10 minutes before peter gabriel takes the stage&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;amazing concert, thunderstorms and rain blowing into the pavilion&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;what a great way to end the vacation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set List:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Rain&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;More Than This&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Secret World&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Games Without Frontiers&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mercy Street&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Darkness&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Digging In The Dirt&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t Give Up&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Tower That Ate People&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Growing Up&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Shock The Monkey&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Solsbury Hill&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sledgehammer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Signal To Noise&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In Your Eyes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Come Talk To Me&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Father, Son&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the best vacation i&amp;#8217;ve ever had. it was nice to not have to stress about money and just enjoy the time we had. It was great to see some friends from college, the one&amp;#8217;s that really mattered, who actually supported all the goofy ideas i had, i miss them both very much.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Brutal cold and Rollins</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2003/01/23/brutal"/>
   <updated>2003-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2003/01/23/brutal</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Brutal cold today (2 degrees this morning), but i think last night was worse (-19 wind chill).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had a great time last night seeing Henry Rollins in Chicago. Pretty solid show. It&amp;#8217;s good to see the changes over the years in his performances. A tough 1.5 hr wait in single digit temperature, but worth it, since we were only three rows back and dead cente.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fantastic drive homeward, right through the city with it&amp;#8217;s amazing buildings all lit up and gorgeous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty awake all things considered, all things being two consistant nights of 4hrs of sleep, but that&amp;#8217;s ok. Soon coffee will be brewing and all will be well.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2002</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2002/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2002-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2002/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally wised up, left Florida and went back to my old gig. It was a big transition year, and I finally decided that I was going to do the IT thing and give up on academia. I had a lot of insights into the college gig thing and was incredibly disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2002&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Two Towers - J.R.R. Tolkien&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Cook&amp;#8217;s Tour - Anthony Bourdain&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Nudist on the Late Shift - Po Bronson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Vision Quest - Terry Davis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fletch - Gregory McDonald&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Deep Blue Goodbye - John D. McDonald&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Grand Opening - Jon Hassler&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Revolutionary Road - Richard Yates&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fight Club - Chuck Pahlanuick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ball Four - Jim Bouton&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Choke - Chuck Pahlanuick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mohawk - Richard Russo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Whore&amp;#8217;s Child - Richard Russo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nightmare in Pink - John D. McDonald&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hollywood Nocturnes - James Ellroy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;October Sky - Homer H. Hickman Jr.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Native Tongue - Carl Hiaasen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Roadkill - Kinky Friedman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Pastoralia - George Saunders&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Skin Tight - Carl Hiassen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Lullabye - Chuck Pahalnuk&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Porno - Irvine Welsch&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Wise Guy - Nicholas Pileggi&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Demonology - Rick Moody&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;My Dark Places - James Ellroy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;L.A. Confidential - James Ellroy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How to Ruin Your Life - Ben Stein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Peter Gabriel Live</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2002/11/15/Peter-Gabriel-Live"/>
   <updated>2002-11-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2002/11/15/Peter-Gabriel-Live</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Amazing show, too much to write about right now. Third time seeing him live, consistantly one of the greatest live performers with a fantastic band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set List (as best as i can remember):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here Comes the Flood&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Darkness&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Red Rain&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Secret World&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sky Blue&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Downside-Up (from Ovo)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Barry Williams Show&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;More Than This&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mercy Street&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Digging In The Dirt&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Growing Up &amp;lt;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8211; maybe the highlight of the show&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sledge Hammer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Solsbury Hill&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Animal Nation (new Tune)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Signal to Noise&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;ENCORE 1: In Your Eyes.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;ENCORE 2: Family Snapshot&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;ENCORE 3: Father, Son.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>gopher</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2002/01/08/gopher"/>
   <updated>2002-01-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2002/01/08/gopher</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;reading old &amp;#8216;issues&amp;#8217; of suck thanks to a link by Dave Winer&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really miss the ol&amp;#8217; cyncism/optimism of the early sprout of the web. On one side was the idealism and world changing mentality that made quite a number of folks very wealthy. Then there was &amp;#8216;suck.com&amp;#8217;, one of the first web sites i can remember visiting (yep, i remember life before the web, and how excited i was by the access to all that information). They&amp;#8217;re cyncism was heroic, an attempt to look at the broader view, and look ahead to to all the dead dot-coms that have fallen. They were completely self-deprecating as well, and far more clever/hip than the onion will ever be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who would have thought ten years ago about the effect of Jerry Yang and David Filo. Amazing what a little vision will bring you. There were alot of &amp;#8216;hereos&amp;#8217; in those early days. It&amp;#8217;s now settled to a quiet yawn, with little bits of &amp;#8216;yowza cool&amp;#8217; technology seeping through at rare moments (and no, the new iMac/desklamp does not qualify!!!) that are usually more subtle and evolve slowly over time. Something so taken for granted such as &amp;#8216;apache&amp;#8217; or the lovely marriage of php and MySQL. These technologies didn&amp;#8217;t emerge with a bang and a holler like &amp;#8216;Java&amp;#8217;, but their impact so far has been far deeper and influential, and much less influenced by the marketing dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps its just the demise of Be. Another great idea born of that early optimism that was quickly despensed of, and will soon be auctioned off in ugly bits and pieces. I never did get a BeBox, but i did read every interview/article with Gassee that i could find. Back then what Negroponte had to say almost mattered &amp;#8230; a little. But his impact seems mostly defined by the description of a &amp;#8216;digital lifestyle&amp;#8217;, whatever the hell that means . .&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2001</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2001/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2001-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2001/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was still in Florida, but my time was coming to an end. After a very disappointing first year at school, I attempted one more year, hoping that the teaching opportunity would help. It was good to finally get into writers such as Richard Russo and Michael Chabon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2001&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let the Dog Drive - David Bowman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Big U - Neal Stephenson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Crypto - Steven Levy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Blue Angel - Francine Prose&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Invisible Mosters - Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Secrets and Lies - Bruce Schneider&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ender&amp;#8217;s Game - Orson Scott Card&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Just for Fun - Linus Tovalds and David Diamond&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Risk Pool - Richard Russo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Plainsong - Kent Haruf&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Turned On - James Parker&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Breakfast of Champions - Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Open Sources - (editors) Chris DiBona, Sam Ockman, Mark Stone&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Think Unix - John Hassler&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Big Bad Love - Larry Brown&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Trailorpark - Russell Banks&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Confidential - Anthony Bourdain&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Straight Man - Richard Russo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Prayer for Owen Meany - John Irving&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Wonderboys - Michael Chabon&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Fellowship of the Ring - J.R.R. Tolkien&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Season on the Brink - John Feinstein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Clarity?</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2001/02/10/clarity"/>
   <updated>2001-02-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2001/02/10/clarity</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nice quick bike-ride home, lots of thoughts. Back in the studio and working on the piece, makes me think a lot about this silly little world i&amp;#8217;m involved in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lifetime of love for music, it&amp;#8217;s my favorite of the arts and IMHO the greatest. But the unfortunate problem is who/what you come in contact with in the world of music (in particular that of academic music). Perhaps that&amp;#8217;s why I still have such a passion for literature, I don&amp;#8217;t know too many writers, if i did, i may come to dislike literature as much as i&amp;#8217;m coming to dislike music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world of academic music is so torn apart by egos and self-fulfilling necessities. My basic premiss is that academic music is much like monopoly money. Outside of its own little world of the game, it has no value, no worth, and no need to exist. Outside of the cloistered walls of academia, this music has no value, no worth, and no need to exist. It exists only because of its creators own self-made ego-driven desire to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s not a fundamental problem with the teaching of arcane art and obscure knowledge. I think academia is very important for that very fact since we never really know when this knowledge may become necessary or important. The is the realm of pure research. The problem I have, is the weakness that crawls through similar programs under the cloak of &amp;#8216;art&amp;#8217;. &amp;#8220;This is my art and if you don&amp;#8217;t like it you don&amp;#8217;t understand it.&amp;#8221; It&amp;#8217;s a very weak and very frustrating problem, since it tends to be of the majority, and therefore drags down that which attempts to go beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not in any way a hatred towards progressive music or pro-pop music. Its not the music itself, but rather the people associated with it. Self-righteous and egotistical. It wouldn&amp;#8217;t bother me at all if there were some level of humility or grace. But instead, it is self-serving ego-driven crap designed only for the self-satisfaction of its creator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure what brought this all on. Perhaps it was the crowd of young music student on campus. I just wanted to scream at them to not study music. If you care at all for it as any sort of relevant art, don&amp;#8217;t let academia drag you down. Stay away, teach yourself, and be awesome in your own way, not under their clueless and short-sighted mold.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 2000</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/2000/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>2000-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/2000/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While work was going well, I was still trying to find a school for a PhD program. I got accepted into what looked like a decent program and left work to live in Florida. My brother introduced me to &amp;#8216;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance&amp;#8217; which was a huge influence on my thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 2000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Girlfriend in a Coma - Douglas Coupland&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Imaginary Girlfriend - John Irving&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Catch 22 - Joseph Heller&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To Boulez and Beyond - Joan Peyser&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Sheltering Sky - Paul Bowles&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Crossing - Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Heartbreaking Work of Staggering Genius - David Eggers&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Geeks - Jon Katz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;House of Leaves - Mark Z. Danielewski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Hotel New Hampshire - John Irving&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sweet Swing Blues on the Road - Wynton Marsalis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Glamorama - Bret Easton Ellis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Snow Crash - Neal Stephenson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cryptonomicon - Neal Stephenson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cities of the Plain - Corman McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Water Method Man - John Irving&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance - Robert M. Pirsig&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Soundpieces 2 - Cole Gagne&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Man Who Loved Only Numbers - Paul Hoffman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;On Writing - Stephen King&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Conversations with Iannis Xenakis - Balint Andras Varga&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Very Persistant Gappers of Frip - George Saunders&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Troublemakers - John McNally&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The End of Alice - A. M. Homes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Music for Torching - A.M. Homes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Open Sky: Sonny Rollins and His World of Improvisation - Eric Nisenson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Smile, You&amp;#8217;re Travelling - Henry Rollins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 1999</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/1999/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>1999-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/1999/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1999 was full of changes. I had finished off the masters program in a year and a half. I had committed to working at a music camp over the summer where I consumed the entire David Foster Wallace collection. I also spent some time traveling and finally had to make a career decision. Although I was accepted into a PhD program, I couldn&amp;#8217;t come up with the funds, so into IT I went. Since I had no real experience, I spent my time preparing for certification exams and finally got my first real job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 1999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Riven Rock - T. Coraghessan Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Poetics of Music - Igor Stravinsky&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dubliners - James Joyce&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sonora - John Zorn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Gates of Eden - Ethan Coen&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Marbourn Stork Nightmare - Irvine Welch&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ambient - Jack Womack&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man - James Joyce&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The World According to Garp - John Irving&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Ginger Man - J. P. Donleary&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Infinite Jest - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Filth - Irvine Welsch&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Girl with Curious Hair - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Grey Area - Will Self&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Supposidly Fun Thing I&amp;#8217;ll Never Do Again - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Broom of the System - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Brief Interviews With Hideous Men - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Naked - David Sedaris&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Invention of Solitude - Paul Auster&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The New York Triology - Paul Auster&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Going Native - Stephan Wright&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;About a Boy - Nick Hornby&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Willow Tree - Hubert Selby Jr.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Quantitive Theory of Insanity - Will Self&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Whores for Gloria - WIlliam T. Vollman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a Slippery Slope - Spalding Gray&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Jaco - Bill Milkowski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Pugilist at Rest - Thom Jones&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Civilwarland in Bad Decline - George Saunders&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tough, Tough Toys for Tough, Tough Boys - Will Self&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Wonders of the Invisible World - David Gates&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All the Pretty Horses - Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Faster - James Gleick&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I Smell Ester Williams - Mark Leyner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Acid House - Irvine Welsch&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sonny Liston was a Friend of Mine - Thom Jones&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Crying of Lot 49 - Thomas Pynchon&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Pattern on the Stone - Daniel Hillis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 1998</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/1998/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>1998-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/1998/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After graduation, I was offered a Teaching Assistantship. Looking back at only having read 13 books over an entire year is almost embarrassing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 1998&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architects of the Web - Robert Reid&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;My Idea of Fun - Will Self&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Exegesis - Astro Teller&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Music Since 1945 - Elliot Schwartz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Anton Von Webern - Malcom Hayes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Proud Highway - Hunter S. Thompson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Digerati - John Brackman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Neon Bible - John Kennedy Toole&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;High Fidelity - Nick Hornby&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;American Pioneers: Ives to Cage and Beyond - Alan Rich&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Talking Music - William Duckworth&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Do I Come Here Often - Henry Rollins&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Solipsist - Henry Rollins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 1997</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/1997/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>1997-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/1997/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1997 was an insanely busy year. I spent most of the time preparing for my solo recital, as well as working three jobs at a time while maintaining a full course load. I was living in a great house that I never saw, and spent up to 50-60 hours a week at the recording studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 1997&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Little Kingdom - Michael Moritz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Being Digital - Nicholas Negroponte&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ladies and Gentleman, Lenny Bruce - Albert Goldman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Downsize This - Michael Moore&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Silicon Snake Oil - Clifford Stoll&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Takedown - Simormura and Markoff&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Masters of Deception - Slatalle and Quittner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Hacker Crackdown - Bruce Sterling&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Fugitive Game - Jonathan Littman&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Year With Swollen Appendicies - Brian Eno&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I Sing the Body Electric - Fred Moody&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Poloroids from the Dead - Douglas Coupland&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tooth Imprints on a Corn Dog - Mark Leyner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Elliot Carter: In Conversation with Enzo Restagno&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Random Acts of Sensless Violence - Jack Womack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 1996</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/1996/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>1996-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/1996/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I purchased my first computer (Apple Performa) in 1996, and my book reading declined exponentially. I started reading more about technology than fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 1996&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Rachel Papers - Martin Amis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Trout Fishing in America - Richard Brautigan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Stranger - Albert Camus&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Road Ahead - Bill Gates&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mishima - John Nathan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;True Story - Bill Maher&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Spike, Mike, Slackers, and Dykes - John Pierson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Rush Limbaugh is a Big Fat Idiot - Al Franken&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Grifters - Jim Thompson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Microserfs - Douglas Coupland&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Insanely Great - Steve Levy&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Screams from the Balcony - Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Tortilla Curtain - T. Coraghessan Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Spirit Catcher - John Fraim&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Neuromancer - William Gibson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Third Apple - Jean Louis Gasse&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Soul of a New Machine - Tracy Kidder&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Crash - J.G. Ballard&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Last of the Savages - Jay McInerny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 1995</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/1995/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>1995-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/1995/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t remember what finally got me into Raymond Carver, but he&amp;#8217;s by far my favorite short-story writer. I remember 1995 as being a very confusing time, and I went through a huge variety of writers that year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 1995&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short Cuts - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Feast of Snakes - Harry Crews&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No Minor Chords - Andre Previn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Frank Zappa: Negative Dialects of Poodle Play - Ben Watson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Knockout Artist - Harry Crews&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tracer - Frederic Barthelme&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Kentucky Ham - William S. Burroughs Jr.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cathedral - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;At Night, the Salmon Move - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Where I&amp;#8217;m Calling From - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Furious Seasons - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ranson - Jay McInerny&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A New Path to the Waterfall - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sex, Lies, and Videotape - Steven Soderberg&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Hawk is Dying - Harry Crews&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Loop - Joe Coomer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ultra-Marine - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Where the Water Comes Together With Other Water - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Pounding Nails in the Floor with my Forehead - Eric Bogosian&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Road to Los Angeles - John Fante&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Carver Country - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Marquis de Sade - Donald Thomas&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Scar Lover - Harry Crews&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No Beast so Fierce - Edward Bunker&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Virtual Light - William Gibson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Will you Please be Quiet, Please? - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Importance of Being Eric Dolphy - Raymond Harricks&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Gurdjieff: A Very Great Enigma - J.G. Bennett&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fires - Raymond Carver&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Strange and Terrible Saga of Hunter S. Thompson - Paul Perry&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tropic of Capricorn - Henry Miller&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Brian Eno - Eric Tamm&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Life After God - Douglas Coupland&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mother: the Frank Zappa Story - Michael Gray&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Suburbia - Eric Bogosian&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Planet Joe - Joe Cole&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Confederacy of Dunces - John Kennedy Toole&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Perfect Pitch - Nicholas Slominsky&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Sadness of Sex - Barry Yourgrau&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Et Tu, Babe - Mark Leyner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Animal Factor - Edward Bunker&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Illuminati Papers - Robert Anton Wilson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dead Babies - Martin Amis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Rommel Drives on Deep into Egypt - Richard Brautigan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 1994</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/1994/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>1994-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/1994/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1994 was more of the same, but I started diving into a large number of musician&amp;#8217;s biographies. It was the first summer that I spent away from home in my first apartment. My roommate and I both worked in restaurants and took classes during the day. I would often hide out in the school library for the free air-conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 1994&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Most Beautiful Woman in Town - Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Job - William S. Burroughs&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Quiet Days in Clichy - Henry Miller&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nights of Love and Laughter - Henry Miller&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Charlie Parker - Brian Priestly&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sonny Rollins - Charles Blanca&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ornette Coleman - John Litwieder&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Beneath the Underdog - Charles Mingus&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Coltrane - C. O. Simpkins&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Chasin the Train - J.C. Thomas&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bird: The Legend of Charlie Parker -&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Free Play - Stephan Nachmanovitch&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;With William Burroughs - Victor Bockris&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mingus/Mingus - Coleman and Young&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Fermata - Nicholson Baker&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Black Spring - Henry Miller&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Drumming at the Edge of Magic - Micky Hart&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Music and Imagination - Aaron Copeland&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Informers - Bret Easton Ellis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;John Coltrane - Bill Cole&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ascension: John Coltrane and his Quest - Eric Nisenson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bird Lives - Ross Rusell&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Americana - Don DeLillo&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Joys and Sorrows - Pablo Casalas&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Life on the Road - Julien Bream&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;World&amp;#8217;s End - T. Coraghessan Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Better than Sex - Hunter S. Thompson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Adding Machine - William S. Burroughs&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Letters to a Young Poet - Rainer Maria Rilke&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bright Lights, Big City - Jay McInerey&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Story of My Life - Jay McIneray&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Blood and Grits - Henry Crews&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Body - Henry Crews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading 1993</title>
   <link href="http://www.mjladd.com/1993/12/31/reading"/>
   <updated>1993-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://www.mjladd.com/1993/12/31/reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1993 was an incredible year for finally having the chance to read so many authors that I&amp;#8217;ve only heard about. I remember spending my typical Friday evenings at college at the Library until it closed at 7:00 pm, and then heading home with a pile of books by Hunter Thompson, Hubert Selby, or Charles Bukowski. I would hole up in my dorm room with a fresh pot of coffee and read for four to five hours before heading out for more typical college fun. During the summer of &amp;#8216;93 I worked at a golf course, where I would spend my lunch break reading &amp;#8216;Tropic of Cancer&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8216;McTeague&amp;#8217; while listening to AM radio in a gigantic, 1976 Black Cutlass Supreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading List 1993&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hells Angels - Hunter S. Thompson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Drinking in America - Eric Bogosian&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Budding Prospects - T. Coraghessan Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ham on Rye - Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas - Hunter S. Thompson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Junky - William S. Burroughs&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Bang - Henry Rollins&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Yage Letters - William S. Burroughs&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;At Terror Street and Agony Way - Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hank: Life of Charles Bukowski - Neeli Cherkovski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Black Coffee Blues - Henry Rollins&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Song of the Silent Snow - Hubert Selby Jr.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Jernigan - David Gates&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Room - Hubert Selby Jr.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Neurologic - Timothy Leary&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cosmic Trigger - Robert Anton Wilson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Water Music - T. Coraghessan Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Barfly - Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Henry Miller&amp;#8217;s Book of Friends - Henry Miller&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mockingbird, Wish me Luck - Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Vox - Nicholson Baker&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Now Watch Him Die - Henry Rollins&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Friendship, Fame and Bestial Myth - Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Women - Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Great Shark Hunt - Hunter S. Thompson&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;And the Ass Saw the Angel - Nick Cave&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Shampoo Planet - Douglas Coupland&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Bell Jar - Sylvia Plath&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In the Belly of the Beast - Jack Henry Abbott&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Road to Wellville - T. Coraghessan Boyle&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tropic of Cancer - Henry Miller&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Catcher in the Rye - J.D. Salinger&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Secret History - Donna Tartt&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Rules of Attraction - Bret Easton Ellis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Post Office - Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;My Cousin, My Gasteroenterologist - Mark Leyner&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;King Ink - Nick Cave&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;McTeague - Frank Norris&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Good Day to Die - Jim Harrison&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Queer - William Burroughs&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Generation X - Douglas Coupland&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;June 30th, June 30th - Richard Brautigan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Loading Mercury with a Pitchfork - Richard Brautigan&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Davis: An Autobiography - Miles Davis&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Notes of a Dirty Old Man - Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>